PRINCE CHARMING
Onward, Chauncey!
To the highest room
of the tallest tower...
PRINCE CHARMING
...where my princess awaits rescue
from her handsome Prince Charming!
GINGERBREAD MAN
This is worse than "Love Letters".
I hate dinner theater!
PINOCCHIO
Me, too.
PRINCE CHARMING
Whoa there, Chauncey!
ACTRESS
Hark! The brave Prince Charming
approacheth.
PRINCE CHARMING
Fear not, fair maiden. I shall slay
the monster that guards you...
PRINCE CHARMING
...then take my place as rightful king.
OLD LADY
What did she say?
AUDIENCE
It's Shrek!
Whoo, Shrek, yeah!
PRINCE CHARMING
Prepare, foul beast...
...to enter into a world of pain
with which you are not familiar!
WAITER
Happy birthday to thee
PRINCE CHARMING
Do you mind?
GINGERBREAD MAN
Do you mind? Boring!
PRINCE CHARMING
Prepare, foul beast...
Someday you'll be sorry.
AUDIENCE
We already are!
PRINCE CHARMING
Mommy...
You're right. I can't let this happen.
PRINCE CHARMING
I can't!
I am the rightful King of Far Far Away.
PRINCE CHARMING
And I promise you this, Mother...
...I will restore dignity to my throne.
PRINCE CHARMING
And this time,
no one will stand in my way.
SHREK
Good morning.
FIONA
Morning breath.
SHREK
I know. Isn't it wonderful?
DONKEY
Good morning, good morning
The sun is shining through
DONKEY
Good morning, good morning
To you
DONKEY
And you!
They grow up so fast.
SHREK
Not fast enough.
PUSS
You'll be filling in
for the King and Queen.
PUSS
Several functions
require your attendance, sir.
SHREK
Great! Let's get started.
DONKEY
Come on, lazybones. Time to get moving!
You need to get a pair ofjammies.
SHREK
I got some sleep and I needed it
Not a lot, just a little bit
SHREK
Someone's always
trying to keep me from it
SHREK
It's a crying shame
It's a royal pain in the neck
SHREK
I knight thee.
DONKEY
If you're filling in for a king,
you should look like one.
DONKEY
Can somebody come in
and work on Shrek?
RAUL
I will see what I can do.
PUSS
Yeah, wow.
FIONA
Is this really necessary?
RAUL
Quite necessary, Fiona.
SHREK
- I'm Shrek, you twit.
PUSS
This isn't a rehearsal, peoples.
Let's see some hustle!
DONKEY
Smiles, everyone! Smiles!
SHREK
I don't know how much longer
I can keep this up.
FIONA
I'm sorry, but can you
just try to grin and bear it?
FIONA
It's just until Dad gets better.
Shrek?
FIONA
You look handsome.
SHREK
Come here, you.
My butt is itching up a storm and
I can't reach it in this monkey suit.
SHREK
Hey, you! Come here. What's your name?
FIDDLESWORTH
Fiddlesworth, sir.
SHREK
Perfect.
MASTER OF CEREMONIES
Ladies and gentlemen...
...Princess Fiona and Sir Shrek!
SHREK
Ahh! You've got it.
A little to the left.
SHREK
That's it! That's good.
Oh, yeah! Scratch
that thing! You're on it.
FIONA
Shrek!
DONKEY
My eye!
WOMAN
What are you doing?
SHREK
Fiona!
SHREK & FIONA
- Are you okay?
- Yeah. I'm fine.
DONKEY
Shrimp! My favorite!
SHREK & FIONA
- That's it! We're leaving!
- Calm down.
SHREK
Calm down? Who do you think
we're kidding? I am an ogre.
SHREK
I'm not cut out for this, Fiona,
and I never will be.
DONKEY
I think that went well.
SHREK
Donkey!
DONKEY
Come on, Shrek!
PUSS
Some people just don't
understand boundaries.
FIONA
Just think. A couple more days
and we'll be back home...
FIONA
...in our vermin-filled shack
strewn with fungus...
FIONA
...and filled with the rotting stench
of mud and neglect.
SHREK
You had me at "vermin-filled".
FIONA
And, um... maybe even the pitter-patter
of little feet on the floor.
SHREK
That's right, the swamp rats
will be spawning.
FIONA
Uh, no.
What I'm thinking of is a little bigger
than a swamp rat.
SHREK
Donkey?
FIONA
No, Shrek. What if, theoretically...
...they were little ogre feet?
SHREK
Honey, let's be rational about this.
Have you seen a baby lately?
SHREK
They just eat and poop, and they cry...
...then they cry when they poop
and poop when they cry.
SHREK
Now, imagine an ogre baby.
They extra-cry and they extra-poop.
FIONA
Shrek, don't you ever think
about having a family?
SHREK
Right now, you're my family.
Somebody better be dying.
KING HAROLD
I'm dying.
QUEEN
Harold?
KING HAROLD
Don't forget
to pay the gardener, Lillian.
QUEEN
Of course, darling.
KING HAROLD
Fiona.
FIONA
Yes, Daddy?
KING HAROLD
I know I made many mistakes with you.
FIONA
It's okay.
KING HAROLD
But your love for Shrek has...
...taught me much.
KING HAROLD
My dear boy...
...I am proud to call you my son.
SHREK
And I'm proud to call you my frog...
...King dad-in-law.
KING HAROLD
Now there is a matter
of business to attend to.
PUSS
The Frog King... is dead.
DONKEY
Put your hat back on, fool.
KING HAROLD
Shrek...
...please come hither.
SHREK
Yeah, Dad?
KING HAROLD
This kingdom needs a new king.
You and Fiona
are next in line for the throne.
SHREK
Next in line. You see, Dad,
that's why people love you.
SHREK
Even on your deathbed,
you're still making jokes.
SHREK
Come on, Dad. An ogre as king?
That's not such a good idea.
SHREK
There must be somebody else. Anybody!
KING HAROLD
Aside from you, there is
only one remaining heir.
SHREK
Really? Who is he, Dad?
KING HAROLD
His name is...
...is...
SHREK
What's his name?
KING HAROLD
...is...
FIONA
Daddy!
KING HAROLD
His name is Arthur.
SHREK
Arthur?
KING HAROLD
I know you'll do...
...what's right.
QUEEN
Harold?
SHREK
Dad? Dad!
Dad?
DONKEY
Do your thing, man.
MUSIC
~ When you were young and your heart ~
~ Was an open book ~
MUSIC
~ You used to say live and let live ~
~ You know you did, you know you did
You know you did ~
MUSIC
~ But if this ever changing world
In which we live in ~
MUSIC
~ Makes you give in and cry ~
~ Say live and let die ~
MUSIC
~ Live and let die ~
~ Hey, lady
You, lady ~
MUSIC
~ Cursing at your life ~
~ You're a discontented mother ~
MUSIC
And a regimented wife ~
PRINCE CHARMING
What does a prince
have to do to get a drink here?
PRINCE CHARMING
Ah, Mabel!
Why they call you an ugly stepsister,
I'll never know.
PRINCE CHARMING
Where's Doris? Taking the night off?
MABEL
She's not welcome here,
and neither are you.
MABEL
What do you want, Charming?
PRINCE CHARMING
Not much. Just a chance at redemption.
And a Fuzzy Navel.
PRINCE CHARMING
And Fuzzy Navels for all my friends!
CAPTAIN HOOKS
We're not your friends.
CAPTAIN HOOK
You don't belong here.
PRINCE CHARMING
You're absolutely right,
but, I mean, do any of us?
CYCLOPS
Do a number on his face.
PRINCE CHARMING
Wait, wait, wait!
We are more alike than you think.
PRINCE CHARMING
Wicked Witch! The Seven Dwarfs
saved Snow White, and what happened?
EVIL QUEEN
Oh, what's it to you?
PRINE CHARMING
They left you the unfairest of them all.
PRINCE CHARMING
Now here you are,
hustling pool to get your next meal.
PRINCE CHARMING
How does that feel?
EVIL QUEEN
pretty unfair.
PRINCE CHARMING
And you!
Your star puppet abandons the show
to go and find his father.
PUPPET MASTER
I hate that little wooden puppet.
PRINCE CHARMING
And Hook.
Need I say more?
PRINCE CHARMING
- And you, Frumpypigskin!
- Rumpelstiltskin.
PRINCE CHARMING
Where's that firstborn
you were promised?
PRINCE CHARMING
Mabel. Remember how you
couldn't get your little fat foot...
PRINCE CHARMING
...into that tiny glass slipper?
Cinderella is
in Far Far Away right now...
PRINCE CHARMING
...eating bonbons, cavorting with
every last fairy tale creature...
PRINCE CHARMING
...that has ever done you wrong!
Once upon a time, someone decided
that we were the losers.
PRINCE CHARMING
But there are
two sides to every story...
PRINCE CHARMING
...and our side has not been told!
So who will join me? Who wants
to come out on top for once?
PRINCE CHARMING
Who wants their...
..."happily ever after"?
BLIND MOUSE
This way, gents.
PUSS
It's out of my hands, senorita. The
winds of fate have blown on my destiny.
PUSS
But I will never forget you.
You are the love of my life.
PUSS
As are you.
And, uh, you.
PUSS
I don't know you, but I'd like to.
I got to go!
DONKEY
I don't wanna leave you either.
But you know how Shrek is.
The dude's lost without me.
DONKEY
But don't worry. I'll send you
airmail kisses every day!
DONKEY
Be strong, babies.
Coco, Peanut, listen to your mama.
DONKEY
Bananas, no roasting marshmallows
on your sister's head.
DONKEY
That's my special boy!
Come here, all of you!
Give your daddy a big hug!
FIONA
Shrek?
Maybe you should just stay and be King.
SHREK
Come on. There's no way
I could ever run a kingdom.
SHREK
That's why your cousin Arthur
is a perfect choice.
FIONA
It's not that, no. You see...
SHREK
And if he gives me any trouble,
I always have persuasion and reason.
SHREK
Here's persuasion... and here's reason.
Fiona...
SHREK
...soon it's just going to be you, me...
...and our swamp.
FIONA
It's not going to be just you and me.
SHIP CAPTAIN
All aboard!
SHREK
It will be. I promise.
I love you.
PIG
That's lovely.
DONKEY
Bye-bye, babies!
FIONA
Shrek!
SHREK
- Wait!
- What is it?
FIONA
I'm... I'm...
SHREK
I love you too, honey!
FIONA
No! I said I'm...
SHREK
You're what?
FIONA
I said I'm pregnant!
SHREK
What was that?
FIONA
You're going to be a father!
SHREK
That's great!
FIONA
Really? I'm glad you think so!
I love you!
SHREK
Yeah!
Me, too! You!
DONKEY
I'm going to be an uncle!
PUSS
And you, my friend, are royally...
SHREK
Home.
FIONA
Shrek!
SHREK
Fiona!
Fiona?
SHREK
Oh, no.
better out than in, I always say.
SHREK
No, no, no!
It's okay. It's gonna be all right.
SHREK
Stop! Hey, wait!
Donkey. Donkey!
DONKEY
Wake up!
OGRE BABY
Dada!
DONKEY
Shrek! You okay?
SHREK
I can't believe I'm going to be
a father. How did this happen?
PUSS
Allow me to explain. You see, when a man
has a certain feeling for a woman...
PUSS
...a powerful urge sweeps over him.
SHREK
I know how it happened.
I just can't believe it.
DONKEY
How does it happen?
MUSIC
~ And the cat's in the cradle
and the silver spoon ~
MUSIC
~ Little Boy Blue and the Man in the Moon ~
~ When you coming home, son?
I don't know when ~
MUSIC
~ But we'll get together then, Dad. ~
SHREK
Donkey! Can you just cut to the part
where you're supposed
to make me feel better?
PUSS
You know I love Fiona, boss. Right?
What I am talking about here
is you, me, my cousin's boat...
PUSS
...an ice cold pitcher of mojitos
and two weeks of nothing but fishing.
DONKEY
Don't listen to him!
Having a baby
is not going to ruin your life.
SHREK
It's not my life I'm worried
about ruining, it's the kid's.
SHREK
I mean, when have you ever heard the phrase
"as sweet as an ogre"...
SHREK
...or "as nurturing as an ogre"...
...or how about "You're gonna love
my dad. He's a real ogre."
DONKEY
Okay. Okay. I get it.
But nobody said it's going to be easy.
But at least you got us to help you.
SHREK
That's true.
I'm doomed.
DONKEY
You'll be fine.
SHIP CAPTAIN
You're finished.
Uh, with your journey.
DONKEY
"Wor-ces-ters-shiree"?
Now that sounds fancy!
SHREK
It's Worcestershire.
DONKEY
Like the sauce? Hmmmmmm!
It's spicy!
DONKEY
Oh, they must be expecting us.
What in the shista-shire
kind of place is this?
SHREK
Well, my stomach aches and my palms
just got sweaty. Must be a high school.
DONKEY
High school?
CHEERLEADERS
Ready? Okay!
Wherefore art thou headed, to the top?
CHEERLEADERS
Yeah, we think so, we think so! And
dost thou thinkest thine can be stopped?
CHEERLEADERS
Nay, we thinkst not, we thinkst not!
DRIVERS ED INSTRUCTOR
All right, Mr. Percival,
ease up on the reins.
VAN STUDENT
For lo, bro, don't burn
all my frankincense and myrrh.
DONKEY
I'm feeling nauseous from memories
of wedgies and swirlies!
PUSS
How did you receive wedgies when you are
clearly not the wearer of the underpants?
DONKEY
Let's just say some things
are better left unsaid.
GUINEVERRE
So I was all like, "I'd rather get
the black plague than go out with you."
TIFFANY
- Oh, totally.
- Pardon me.
TIFFANY
- Totally ew-eth.
- Yeah, totally.
GARY
I just altered my character level
to +3 superb-ability.
SHREK
Hi. We're looking for someone named...
GARY
Who rolled a +9 dork spell and
summoned the beast and his quadruped?
SHREK
I know you're busy not fiting in, but
can either of you tell me where I can find Arthur?
GARY
He's over there.
LANCELOT
There is no sweeter taste
on thy tongue than victory!
SHREK
Strong, handsome, face of a leader.
Does Arthur look like a king or what?
SHREK
Sorry.
ARTIE
Did you say you were looking for Arthur?
PUSS
That information is
on a need-to-know basis.
DONKEY
It's top secret!
LANCELOT
Now, gentlemen, let's away.
To the showers!
SHREK
Greetings, Your Majesty.
This is your lucky day.
LANCELOT
What are you supposed to be?
Some kind of giant mutant leprechaun
or something?
SHREK
Giant mutant... You made a funny.
LANCELOT
Unhand me, monster!
SHREK
Stop squirming, Arthur.
LANCELOT
I'm not Arthur.
I am Lancelot.
LANCELOT
That dork over there is Arthur.
GUINEVERRE
This is, like, totally embarrassing...
...but Tiffany thinkest
thou vex her so soothly.
GUINEVERRE
She thought perchance thou would
ask her to the Homecoming Dance.
SHREK
Excuse me?
GUINEVERRE
Like, whatever. She's totally into college guys
and mythical creatures.
SHREK
Oh, Arthur...
...come out, come out, wherever you are!
DONKEY
You better run,
you little punk no-goodniks!
DONKEY
The days of Donkey Dumpy Drawers
are over!
HALL MONITOR
Hold it.
COSTUME STUDENT
We're here for the mascot contest.
SHREK
We're here for the mascot contest, too.
HALL MONITOR
This is a costume?
SHREK
Worked on it all night long.
HALL MONITOR
Looks pretty real to me.
PUSS
If he were real, could I do this?
DONKEY
Or this?
SHREK
If it were real, that would have been
agonizingly painful.
DONKEY & SHREK
- Now watch this!
- That's quite enough, boys.
PRINCIPAL PYNCHLEY
Thank you to Professor Primbotom
and his lecture...
PRINCIPAL PYNCHLEY
...on "just say nay".
And now, without further ado, let's give
a warm Worcestershire hoozah...
PRINCIPAL PYNCHLEY
...to the winner
of our mascot contest, the...
PRINCIPAL PYNCHLEY
...ogre?
SHREK
That's right. I'm the new mascot.
So let's really try and beat
the other guys at...
SHREK
...whatever it is they're doing!
PRINCIPAL PYNCHLEY
This is all a bit unorthodox...
SHREK
Where can I find Arthur Pendragon?
Hey, wait...
LANCELOT
Classic.
DONKEY
You should be ashamed of yourself!
LANCELOT
I didn't do it. They did.
ARTIE
Please don't eat me.
STUDENTS
Eat him! Eat him! Eat him!
SHREK
I'm not here to eat him!
Time to pack up
your toothbrush and jammies.
SHREK
You're the new King of Far Far Away.
ARTIE
What?
LANCELOT
Artie a king?
More like the Mayor of Loserville!
LANCELOT
Burn.
ARTIE
Is this for real?
SHREK
Absolutely. Clean out your locker, kid.
You got a kingdom to run.
ARTIE
So, wait... l'm really the only heir?
SHREK
The one and only.
ARTIE
Give me... just a second.
My good people...
ARTIE
...I think there's a lesson here for all of us.
Maybe the next time you're about to dunk a kid's
head in a chamber pot, you'll stop and think,
ARTIE
"Hey, maybe this guy has feelings.
Maybe I should cut him some slack.
ARTIE
'Cause maybe... just maybe...
...this guy's gonna turn out to be,
I don't know, a king?
ARTIE
And maybe his first royal decree will be to
banish everyone who ever picked on him."
ARTIE
That's right, I'm looking at you, jousting team!
And Guin? Oh, Guin.
ARTIE
I've always loved you.
Good friends, it breaks my heart, but...
ARTIE
...enjoy your stay here in prison
while I rule the free world baby!
SHREK
Okay, let's not overdo it.
ARTIE
I'm building my city, people...
on rock 'n' roll!
SHREK
You just overdid it.
SNOW WHITE
Look at you!
You look darling.
SLEEPING BEAUTY
Just precious. Look at her.
RAPUNZEL
Any cravings since you got pregnant?
FIONA
No. Not at all.
Do you smell ham?
SNOW WHITE
It's present time!
CINDERALLA
Fiona, please open mine first.
It's... It's the one in front.
FIONA
"Congratulations on your new
mess mak..." Oh, mess maker!
FIONA
"Hopefully this helps.
Love, Cinderella."
DORIS
Look at that!
CINDERALLA
It's for the poopies.
SLEEPING BEAUTY
Wait... babies poop?
RAPUNZEL
Everyone poops, Beauty.
PIG
Fiona!
We all chipped in
for a little present, too.
PIG
Ta-da!
GINGERBREAD MAN
You know the baby's gonna love it,
because I do!
FIONA
Guys, that's so sweet. Thank you.
Who's this one from?
SNOW WHITE
I got you the biggest one,
because I love you most.
SNOW WHITE
"Have one on me. Love, Snow White."
FIONA
What is it?
SNOW WHITE
He's a live-in babysitter.
NANNY DWARF
Where's the baby?
FIONA
You're too kind, Snow,
but I can't accept this.
SNOW WHITE
It's nothing. I have six more at home.
NANNY DWARF
- What does he do?
- The cleaning.
NANNY DWARF
- The feeding.
- The burping.
FIONA
So, what are
Shrek and I supposed to do?
RAPUNZEL
Now you have plenty of time
to work on your marriage.
SHREK
Thanks, Rapunzel.
What's that supposed to mean?
RAPUNZEL
Come on now, Fiona.
You know what happens.
SLEEPING BEAUTY
You're tired all the time.
SNOW WHITE
You start leting yourself go.
GINGERBREAD MAN
Stretch marks.
RAPUNZEL
Say goodbye to romance.
FIONA
I'm sorry, but how many
of you have kids?
DORIS
She's right!
A baby will only strengthen the love
Shrek and Fiona have.
DORIS
How did Shrek react when you told him?
Tell me!
FIONA
When he first found out, Shrek said...
PRINCE CHARMING
Onward, my new friends!
To our happily ever afters!
PRINCE CHARMING
Now... bombs away!
CAPTAIN HOOK
Well, well, well. If it isn't Peter Pan.
MOTHER
- His name's not Peter.
- Shut it, Wendy.
PRINCE CHARMING
Enough pillaging! To the castle!
GINGERBREAD MAN
You go! Take care of the baby!
SNOW WHITE
Everybody stay calm! We're all going to die!
FIONA
Everyone in! Now!
PRINCE CHARMING
Come on! Put some back into it!
FIONA
We don't have time. Now go!
QUEEN
Quickly, ladies!
GINGERBREAD MAN
We'll hold them off as long as we can!
PRINCE CHARMING
Where are Shrek and Fiona?
GINGERBREAD MAN
The name doesn't ring a bell.
PIG
No bell.
PRINCE CHARMING
I suggest you freaks cooperate...
...with the new King of Far Far Away!
GINGERBREAD MAN
The only thing you're ever gonna
be king of is King of the Stupids!
PRINCE CHARMING
- Hook!
- Right!
CAPTAIN HOOK
Avast, ye cookie.
Start talking.
MUFFIN MAN & GINGERBREAD MAN
- Gingy!
- Papa!
TEACHER
Settle down now.
GINGERBREAD MAN
On the good ship Lollipop
It's a sweet trip to the candy shop
PRINCE CHARMING
You!
You can't lie.
PRINCE CHARMING
So tell me, puppet... where is Shrek?
PINOCCHIO
Well... I don't know where he's not.
PRINCE CHARMING
You don't know where Shrek is?
PINOCCHIO
It wouldn't be inaccurate to assume...
...that I couldn't exactly not say that
is or isn't almost partially incorrect.
PRINCE CHARMING
So you do know where he is!
PINOCCHIO
On the contrary,
I'm possibly more or less
PINOCCHIO
not definitely rejecting the idea
that in no way,
with any amount of uncertainty...
PRINCE CHARMING
Stop it!
PINOCCHIO
...I do not know where he shouldn't probably be.
If that indeed wasn't where he isn't.
PINOCCHIO
Even if he wasn't not where
I knew he was, it could mean...
GINGERBREAD MAN
On the good ship Lollipop
PIG
Enough! Shrek went off
to bring back the next heir!
PRINCE CHARMING
He's bringing back the next heir?
PINOCCHIO
No!
PRINCE CHARMING
Hook! Get rid of this new "King".
But bring Shrek to me.
PRINCE CHARMING
I have something special
in mind for him.
PINOCCHIO
He'll never fall for your tricks!
WOLF
Oh, boy.
ARTIE
I can't believe it. Me, a king?
I knew I came from royalty and all, but...
ARTIE
...I figured everyone forgot about me.
SHREK
Oh, no. In fact the King
asked for you personally.
ARTIE
Really? Wow.
But I know it's not all fun and games.
SHREK
It really is
all fun and games, actually.
SHREK
Sure, you have to knight a few heroes,
launch a ship or two.
SHREK
By the way, make sure you hit the boat
just right with the bottle.
ARTIE
Any idiot can hit a boat with the bottle.
SHREK
Well, I've heard
it's harder than it looks.
ARTIE
This is going to be huge.
Parties, princesses,
castles. Princesses.
DONKEY
You'll be living in the lap of luxury.
The got the finest chefs
will wait for your order.
PUSS
And fortunately,
you'll have the royal food tasters.
ARTIE
What do they do?
PUSS
Taste the food before the King eats,
to make sure it's not poisoned.
ARTIE & SHREK
- Poisoned?
- Or too salty.
DONKEY
Don't worry about it. Your bodyguards
will keep you safe.
PUSS
All of them willing
at a moment's notice
PUSS
to lay down their lives
out of devotion to you.
ARTIE
Really?
PUSS
The whole kingdom will look
to you for wisdom and guidance.
DONKEY
Make sure they don't die of famine!
PUSS & DONKEY
- Or plague.
- Plague is bad.
PUSS
The coughing, the groaning,
the festering sores.
SHREK
Festering sores!
You are one funny kity cat.
PUSS
What did I say?
SHREK
We don't want Artie
geting the wrong idea.
SHREK
Artie?
SHIP CAPTAIN
There goes my hip!
SHREK
Artie! What are you doing?
ARTIE
What does it look like?!
SHREK
This really isn't up to you.
ARTIE
I don't know anything about being king!
SHREK
You'll learn on the job!
ARTIE
Sorry to disapoint you, but I'm going back.
SHREK
Back to what? Being a loser?
Now look what you did!
ARTIE
Look what I did?
Who's holding the wheel, chief?
SHREK
Shrek!
SHIP CAPTAIN
Land ho!
PUSS
How humiliating.
SHREK
Oh, nice going, Your Highness.
ARTIE
Now it's "Your Highness"?
What happened to "loser"?
SHREK
If you think this is geting you
out of anything, well it isn't.
SHREK
We're heading back to Far Far Away
one way or another...
SHREK
...and you're going to be a father!
ARTIE
What?
DONKEY
You just said "father".
SHREK
King! You're going to be king!
ARTIE
"You're going to be king!" Yeah, right.
Where do you think you are going?
ARTIE
Far Far Away... from you!
SHREK
You get back here, young man,
and I mean it !
PUSS
Boss? I don't think he's coming back.
Maybe it's for the best.
He's not exactly king material.
DONKEY
When did you plan to tell him
you were supposed to be king?
SHREK
Come on. Why would I do that?
Besides, he'll be ten times
better at it than me.
DONKEY
Then you're gonna change your tactics
if you want to get anywhere with him.
SHREK
You're right, Donkey.
What about this?
SHREK & DONKEY
- Shrek!
- Come on. It's just a joke.
SHREK
Still...
Listen, Artie.
SHREK
If you think this whole mad scene
ain't dope, I feel you, dude.
SHREK
I'm not trying to get up in your grill
or raise your roof, or whatever.
SHREK
But what I am screamin' is, yo...
...check out this
kazing thazing, bazaby!
SHREK
If it doesn't groove, or what I'm saying
SHEK
ain't straight trippin',
say, "Oh, no, you didn't!
SHREK
You're getting on my last nerve."
And then I'll know it's...
I'll know it's wack!
ARTIE
Somebody, help!
I've been kidnapped by a monster
who's trying to relate to me!
SHREK & ARTIE
- Artie, wait.
- Come on! Help! Hello?
MERLIN
Greetings, cosmic children
of the universe.
MERLIN
Welcome to my serenity circle.
Please leave any bad vibes
outside the healing vortex.
MERLIN
Now prepare to...
I knew I should have got that warranty!
ARTIE
Mr. Merlin?
SHREK
You know this guy?
ARTIE
Yeah. He was the school magic teacher,
until he had his nervous breakdown.
MERLIN
Technically, I was merely a victim
of a level 3 fatigue.
MERLIN
At the request of my therapist,
and the school authorities, I retired
to the tranquility of nature
MERLIN
to discover my divine purpose.
Now, can I interest anyone
in a snack or beverage?
SHREK
Uh, no.
MERLIN
Sure you don't want to try
my famous Rock Au Gratin?
MERLIN
It's organic.
SHREK
Thanks. I just ate a boulder on the way in.
What we need, are directions
back back to Far Far Away.
ARTIE
"We"? Who said I was going with you?
SHREK
I did. People are counting on you,
so don't try to weasel out of it.
ARTIE
If it's such a great job, you do it.
SHREK
Understand this, kid. It's no more
Mr. Nice Guy from here on out.
ARTIE
So, that was your Mr. Nice Guy?
SHREK
Yeah, and I'm going to miss him.
ARTIE
You know what ?
Why don't you go terrorize a village
and leave me alone!
SHREK
Was that a crack about ogres? You get
your royal highness to Far Far Away...
SHREK
...before I kick it there!
Now, which way am I kicking?
MERLIN
I could have tell you, but since you're
in the midst
of a self-destructive rage spiral,
MERLIN
it would be karmically irresponsible.
SHREK
Self-destructive?
Look, are you going to help us or not?
MERLIN
Most definitely, but only after you
take the journey to your soul!
SHREK
Yeah, I don't think so.
MERLIN
It's either that
or some primal scream therapy.
SHREK
All right, all right.
Journey to the soul.
MERLIN
Now, all of you,
look into the Fire of Truth
MERLIN
and tell me what you see.
DONKEY
Ooh, charades!
Okay, I see a Dutch fudge torte
with cinnamon swirls!
MERLIN
Okay, monster... go for it.
SHREK
I see a rainbow pony.
MERLIN
Excellent work! Now the boy.
ARTIE
This is lame.
MERLIN
You're lame! Now just go for it.
ARTIE
Okay.
There's a baby bird and a father bird
siting in a nest.
MERLIN
Yes! Stay with it!
ARTIE
The dad just flew away. Why did
he leave the little bird all alone?
ARTIE
It's trying to fly,
but it doesn't know how to.
ARTIE
It's going to fall!
MERLIN
Proper head case you are.
Really messed up.
ARTIE
Okay, I get it. The bird's me.
My dad left. So what?
SHREK
Look, Artie, um...
Just thought I'd help set the mood...
SHREK
...for your big heart-to-heart chat.
I know what it's like
to not feel ready for something.
SHREK
Even ogres get scared.
You know... once in a while.
ARTIE
I know you want me
to be king, but I can't.
ARTIE
I'm not cut out for it,
and I never will be, all right?
ARTIE
Even my own dad knew
I wasn't worth the trouble.
ARTIE
He dumped me at that school
the first chance he got...
ARTIE
...and I never heard from him again.
SHREK
My dad wasn't really
the fatherly type, either.
ARTIE
Well, I doubt he was worse than mine.
SHREK
Oh, yeah?
My father was an ogre.
He tried to eat me.
SHREK
Now I guess I should have seen it coming.
He bathed me in barbecue sauce and
put me to bed with an apple in my mouth.
ARTIE
Okay, I guess that's pretty bad.
SHREK
you know, it may be hard to believe,
what, with my obvious charm
and good looks,
SHREK
but people used
to think I was a monster.
SHREK
And for a long time, I believed them.
But after a while,
SHREK
you learn to ignore
the names people call you
SHREK
and you just trust who you are.
ARTIE
You know... you're okay, Shrek.
You just need to do a little less
yelling and use a little more soap.
SHREK
Thanks, Artie.
ARTIE
The soap's because
you stink... really bad.
SHREK
Yeah... I got that.
CINDERELLA
This place is filthy!
I feel like a hobo.
SNOW WHITE
I'm sorry, but this
isn't just working for me.
SLEEPING BEAUTY
Everything's always about you, isn't it.
Something in your attitude is not helping.
SNOW WHITE
Maybe it just bothers you
I was voted fairest in the land.
RAPUNZEL
Oh you mean in that rigged election?
SNOW WHITE
Oh give me a break. "Rapunzel, Rapunzel...
...let down thy golden extensions!"
QUEEN
Ladies, let go of your pety complaints
and let's work together!
SNOW WHITE
So I guess the plan is
we just wander aimlessly
SNOW WHITE
in this stinkhole until we rot.
FIONA
No, we get inside and find out
what Charming's up to.
DORIS
I know he's a jerk and everything,
but that Charming
makes me hotter than July.
FIONA
That's it!
RAPUNZEL
Come on! This way!
FIONA
Rapunzel, wait!
Charming, let go of her.
PRINCE CHARMING
But why would I want to do that?
FIONA
What?
PRINCE CHARMING
Say hello, ladies,
to the new Queen of Far Far Away.
FIONA
Rapunzel, how could you?
RAPUNZEL
Jealous much?
PRINCE CHARMING
Soon you'll be back
where you started,
PRINCE CHARMING
scrubbing floors
or locked away in towers.
PRINCE CHARMING
That is, if I let you last the week.
RAPUNZEL
But Pookie, you promised not to hurt them.
PRINCE CHARMING
Not here, kitten whiskers.
Daddy will discuss it later.
PRINCE CHARMING
Now forgive us.
We have a show to put on.
FIONA
Shrek will be back soon, Charming
and you'll be sorry.
PRINCE CHARMING
Sorry?!
Don't you realize once Shrek
sets foot in Far Far Away...
PRINCE CHARMING
...he's doomed?
DONKEY
Look out! They got a piano!
CAPTAIN HOOK
Kill them all... except the fat one.
King Charming has something special
in mind for you, ogre.
SHREK
King Charming?
CAPTAIN HOOK
Attack!
SHREK
Artie, duck!
CAPTAIN HOOK
Ready the plank!
DONKEY & ARTIE
- Shrek!
- Help!
CAPTAIN HOOK
Cowards!
SHREK
What has Charming done with Fiona?
CAPTAIN HOOK
She's gonna get what's coming to her.
And there ain't nothing
you can do to stop him!
PUSS & DONKEY
- We've got to save her.
- But she's so far far away!
SHREK
Get yourself back
to Worcestershire, kid.
ARTIE
No, Shrek. Hold on a second.
I've got an idea.
MERLIN
I am a buzzing bee.
ARTIE
Mr. Merlin?
They need a spell to get them...
ARTIE
...I mean us, back to Far Far Away.
MERLIN
Forget it. I don't have that kind
of magic in me anymore, kid.
MERLIN
How about a hug?
That's the best kind of magic.
ARTIE
Mr merlin, please. I know you can do it.
MERLIN
I said forget it!
ARTIE
But...
MERLIN
What's with you?
ARTIE
It's just so hard, you know?
They really need to get back,
'cause their kingdom's in trouble.
ARTIE
'Cause there's a really bad man.
And it's just so hard!
MERLIN
Take it easy.
ARTIE
No! I don't think you understand!
There's a mean person doing
mean things to good people.
SHREK
Have a heart, old man.
ARTIE
They really need your help to get them back.
So why won't you help them?!
MERLIN
Okay.
I'll go get my things.
ARTIE
Piece of cake.
SHREK
Well, well. You want eggs with that ham?
MERLIN
I am a little rusty, so there
could be some side effects.
DONKEY & MERLIN
- Side effects?
- Don't worry.
MERLIN
Whatever it is, no matter
how excruciatingly painful it may be,
MERLIN
it will wear off eventually. I think.
MERLIN & DONKEY
- Oops.
- Are you sure this is a good idea?
SHREK
Look, if Artie trusts him,
that's good enough for me.
SHREK
Even if his robe doesn't quite cover...
MERLIN
Alacritious... Expeditious...
...a-zoomy-zoom-zoom!
MERLIN
Let's help our friends get back...
...soon!
MERLIN
It worked!
DONKEY
I haven't been on a trip
like that since college!
SHREK
Donkey?
DONKEY
What? Is something in my teeth?
Oh, no! I've been abracadabra-ed into
a Fancy Feastin', second-rate sidekick!
PUSS
At least you don't look
like some kind of bloated roasted pinata!
PUSS
You should think about going on a diet!
DONKEY
You should get yourself a pair of pants.
I feel all exposed and nasty!
DONKEY
So you two think this is funny?
ARTIE
I'm really sorry, guys.
SHREK
Don't be. You got us back, kid.
DONKEY
How in the Hans Christian Andersen
am I supposed to parade around
in these goofy boots?
PUSS
Hey, hey, hey!
Be very careful with those.
PUSS
They were made in Madrid
by the finest...
DONKEY
You'll learn to control that.
Seriously. Ow! You need some comfort
inserts or arch supports or something.
EVIL DWARF
Watch it. I'm walking here
and I'm gonna keep going until...
SHREK
Pinocchio!
PINOCCHIO
Shrek! Help me!
SHREK & PINOCCHIO
- What happened?
- Charming and the villains
have taken over everything!
PINOCCHIO
Fiona and the Princesses got away.
And now she's...
SHREK
She's what?! What?!
Puss! Loan me five bucks.
DONKEY
You heard him. Help the brother out.
PUSS
Do you see any pockets on me?
DONKEY
Hold on a second.
PUSS
I had no idea, really. I... I swear.
SHREK
Quick Pinocchio! Where is Fiona?
PINOCCHIO
Charming has her locked away
someplace. You have to find him!
PINOCCHIO
He's probably getting ready
for the show!
SHREK
Wait, Pinocchio! What show?
PINOCCHIO
"It's a Happily Ever After After All".
SHREK
"Shrek's final performance"?
DONKEY
Wow, Shrek! You didn't tell us
you were in a play!
SHREK
Well I guess I've been so busy
I forgot to mention it.
GUARD
It's the ogre! Get him!
PUSS
Don't worry, jefe. I got this.
GUARD
Uck! Kill it!
ARTIE
Look. Don't you know who
he thinks he is? How dare you!
SHREK
Donkey, we're dealing with amateurs.
ARTIE
He's a star, people! Hello?
I'm so sorry about this, Mr. Shrek.
SHREK
I'm going to lose it!
ARTIE
I assume everything is ready for tonight?
You did get the list for the dressing room?
DONKEY
yeah, the breakfast croissant stuffed
with seared sashimi tuna.
DONKEY
And I hope you have the saffron corn
with jalapeno honey buter.
DONKEY
Our client cannot get
into his proper emotional state
DONKEY
without jalapeno honey buter!
SHREK
I just lost it.
GUARD
maybe they should talk to Nancy
in Human Resources.
PUSS
Oh, we will have much to say
to Nancy, I promise!
PRINCE CHARMING
"With this sword, I do..." No. "With..."
"With this sword, I do smote thee!"
PRINCE CHARMING
Is "smote" the right word? "Smoot"?
I don't think that's a word, actually.
PRINCE CHARMING
Maybe I should just "smite" him.
Let's try this again. Now...
PRINCE CHARMING
Shrek attacks me.
I pretend to be afraid.
PRINCE CHARMING
"Now the kingdom will get the happily
ever after they deserve. Die, ogre!"
PRINCE CHARMING
Blah, blah, blah. Oh,
it just doesn't feel real enough yet!
PRINCE CHARMING
Who told you to stop dancing?!
CYCLOPS
Wink and turn.
PRINCE CHARMING
What are you laying around for?
Get up! Honestly!
PRINCE CHARMING
Our happily ever after
is nearly complete, Mummy.
PRINCE CHARMING
And I assure you...
...the people of this kingdom
will pay dearly for every second...
PRINCE CHARMING
...we've had to wait.
SHREK
Break a leg.
On second thought,
let me break it for you.
PRINCE CHARMING
Thank goodness, you're here. I was afraid
you wouldn't get back in time.
SHREK
Where's Fiona?
PRINCE CHARMING
Don't worry. She and the others
are safe... for now.
PRINCE CHARMING
Let me guess. Arthur.
ARTIE
It's Artie, actually.
PRINCE CHARMING
This boy is supposed to be
the new King of Far Far Away?
PRINCE CHARMING
How pathetic.
Now, stand still, so I won't make a mess.
SHREK
Charming, stop! I'm here now.
You got what you wanted.
SHREK
This isn't about him.
ARTIE
Then who's it about?
I'm supposed to be king, right?
SHREK
You weren't really next in line
for the throne, okay.
SHREK
I was.
ARTIE
But you said the King
asked for me personally.
SHREK
Not exactly.
ARTIE
What that supposed to mean?
SHREK
I said whatever I had to say, all right?
I wasn't right for the job,
I just needed some fool to replace me.
SHREK
And you fit the bill. So... So just go!
ARTIE
You were playing me the whole time.
SHREK
You catch on real fast, kid.
Maybe you're not
as big of a loser as I thought.
ARTIE
You know, for a minute there...
ARTIE & PRINCE CHARMING
...I actually thought...
- What?
PRINCE CHARMING
That he cared about you? He's an ogre.
PRINCE CHARING
What did you expect?
PRINCE CHARMING
You really do have a way
with children, Shrek.
MUSIC
~ Leave me out with the waste ~
~ This is not what I do ~
MUSIC
~ It's the wrong time ~
~ She's pulling me through ~
MUSIC
~ It's a small crime ~
~ And I got no excuse ~
MUSIC
~ And is that all right, yeah? ~
~ Is that all right with you? ~
MUSIC
~ Is that all right, yeah? ~
~ If I give my gun away when it's loaded? ~
MUSIC
~ If you don't shoot it
how am I supposed to hold it? ~
MUSIC
~ Is that all right?
Is that all right? ~
MUSIC
~ Is that all right with you? ~
~ No. ~
MUSIC
SNOW WHITE
Had we stayed put like I suggested,
we could be sipping tea
out of little heart-shaped cups.
CINDERELLA
Yeah, heart-shaped cups.
SNOW WHITE
And eating crumpets
smothered with loganberries.
CINDERELLA
Yeah, loganberries.
SNOW WHITE & CINDERELLA
- Shut up, Cindy.
- Yeah, shut up.
CINDERELLA
- No, you shut up.
- Stay out of this.
SNOW WHITE
Who cares who's "running the kingdom" anyway?
FIONA & QUEEN
- I care.
- And you should all care too.
DONKEY
I have your badge number, tin can!
DONKEY & FIONA
- Donkey?
- Princess!
FIONA
Puss?
PUSS
I am Puss, stuck here
inside this hideous body.
DONKEY
And I'm me!
FIONA
But you're...
DONKEY
I know, I know, everything's fruity in the loops,
but what happened is
DONKEY
we went to high school,
and the boat crashed
DONKEY
and we got bippity-boppity-booped
by the magic man.
DORIS
You poor sweet things.
CINDERELLA
I don't get it.
SNOW WHITE
The cat turned into a little horse
that smells like feet. What's to get?
SLEEPING BEAUTY
Who dat?
FIONA
Where's Shrek?
DONKEY
Charming has him. He plans to kill Shrek
tonight in front of the whole kingdom!
FIONA
All right, everyone.
We need to find a way out now.
SNOW WHITE
You're right.
Ladies, assume the position!
FIONA
What are you doing?
SLEEPING BEAUTY
Waiting to be rescued.
FIONA
You've got to be kidding me.
SNOW WHITE
What do you expect us to do? We're just four...
...I mean three, super-hot princesses...
SNOW WHITE
...two circus freaks, a pregnant ogre
and an old lady!
QUEEN
Excuse me. Old lady coming through.
FIONA
Mom!
QUEEN
You didn't actually think you got your fighting
skills from your father, did you?
SNOW WHITE
Excuse me. I think there's still one more.
FIONA
Why don't you just lie down?
Okay, girls, from here on out...
FIONA
...we're gonna take care of business ourselves.
ANNOUNCER
Ladies and gentlemen,
The Far Far Away Theatre at the
Charming Pavilion is proud to present...
ANNOUNCER
..."It's A Happily Ever After
After AII."
EVIL KNIGHT
Enjoy your evening
of theatrical reverie, citizen.
EVIL KNIGHT
Oi! No food or beverages in the theater!
PRINCE CHARMING
Places, everyone!
SHREK
Easy!
CYCLOPS
Sorry. I guess I was showing off
for the little one.
CYCLOPS
It's Bring Your Kids to Work Day.
Come here, beautiful.
SHREK
Well, she's got your eye.
CYCLOPS
Who would have thought a monster like
me deserved something as special as you?
SNOW WHITE
~ Little birdies, take wing ~
~ Flitting down from the trees they appear ~
SNOW WHITE
~ And to chirp in my ear ~
~ All because I sing ~
FIONA
Move it! Go!
DONKEY
My babies!
PUSS
Help!
DORIS
Hey, how's it goin'?
PUSS
O to the K. The coast is clear.
DONKEY
All right people, let's do this thing.
Go, Team Dynamite!
PINOCCHIO
I thought we agreed go by the name
Team Super Cool.
GINGERBREAD MAN
I recall it was Team Awesome.
WOLF
I voted for Team Alpha Wolf Squadron.
DONKEY
All right, all right, all right!
From henceforth,
DONKEY
We will be known as Team Alpha Super Awesome
Cool Dynamite Wolf Squadron.
PIG
Ach de liebe! There is some strange
little girl over there staring at us!
DONKEY
Artie!
PUSS
Wait, wait!
Where is the fire, senor?
ARTIE
Please. Don't act so innocent.
You both knew what was going on
and kept it to yourselves.
DONKEY
Artie, it's not like it seems.
ARTIE
It's not? I think it seems pretty clear.
He was using me. That's all.
DONKEY
Using you? You really don't get it.
PUSS
Shrek only said
those things to protect you.
DONKEY
Charming was going to kill you, Artie!
Shrek saved your life.
RUMPLESTILTSKIN
Cue the spot!
RAPUNZEL
~ I wait alone up here ~
~ I'm trapped another day ~
RAPUNZEL
~ Locked up here, please set me free ~
~ My new life I almost see ~
RAPUNZEL
~ A castle, you and me ~
~ Yes, a castle, you and me ~
RUMPLESTILTSKIN
Cherubs!
PRINCE CHARMING
~ Tis I, Tis I
Upon my regal steed ~
PRINCE CHARMING
~ Princess, my love ~
~ At last you shall be freed
I'm strong ~
PRINCE CHARMING
~ And brave
And dashing my way there ~
PRINCE CHARMING
~ With speed! With might!
With soft and bouncy hair! ~
PRINCE CHARMING
~ - Through the blistering desert
- Hot! ~
PRINCE CHARMING
~ - Across the stormiest sea
- Wet! ~
PRINCE CHARMING
~ Facing creatures so vile ~
~ Foul! ~
PRINCE CHARMING
~ So you can gaze upon me! ~
RAPUNZEL
~ I knew you'd come for me ~
~ And now we finally meet ~
PRINCE CHARMING
~ I knew you'd wait ~
~ And from my plate of love you'd eat ~
PRINCE CHARMING
~ Who is this terribly ugly fiend
Who so rudely intervened? ~
PRINCE CHARMING
~ Will Charming fight or flee? ~
~ Oh please rescue me! ~
PRINCE CHARMING
~ From this monstrosity! ~
~ Fear thee not, honey lamb!
I will slice this thing up like a ham! ~
SHREK
Oh, boy.
PRINCE CHARMING
~ You are about to enter a world of pain ~
~ With which you are not familiar! ~
SHREK
Well, it can't be any more painful
than your lousy performance you're giving.
RUMPLESTILTSKIN
"Prepare, foul beast."
PRINCE CHARMING
~ Prepare, foul beast, your time is done! ~
SHREK
Could you kill me and then sing?
PRINCE CHARMING
Be quiet!
SHREK
Come on, I'm just having fun with you.
That's actually a very nice leotard.
PRINCE CHARMING
Thank you.
SHREK
Do they come in men's sizes?
CAPTAIN HOOK
Now that be funny!
PRINCE CHARMING
Enough!
Now you'll finally
know what it's like...
PRINCE CHARMING
...to have everything you worked for...
...everything that's precious to you,
taken away.
PRINCE CHARMING
Now you'll know how I felt.
PIG
Sausage roll!
PUSS
Pray for mercy from Puss!
DONKEY
And Donkey!
D
SHREK
Hi, honey.
FIONA
Sorry we're late. You okay?
SHREK
Much better, now that you're here.
So, Charming, you want to let me out of
these so we can settle this ogre-to-man?
PRINCE CHARMING
Ooh, that sounds fun.
But I have a better idea.
SHREK & FIONA
- Fiona!
- No! Let go of me!
PRINCE CHARMING
You will not ruin things
this time, ogre. Kill it.
ARTIE
Everybody, stop!
PRINCE CHARMING
Oh, what is it now?!
SHREK
Artie?
ARTIE
Who really thinks we need
to settle things this way?
ARTIE
You're telling me you want to be villains
your whole lives?
CAPTAIN HOOK
But we are villains!
It's the only thing we know.
ARTIE
Did you never wish
you could be something else?
EVIL TREE
It's easy for you to say. You're not
some evil enchanted tree.
PRINCE CHARMING
You morons! Don't listen to him! Attack!
EVIL TREE
What Steve's trying too say is
it's hard to come by honest work
EVIL TREE
when the whole world's against you.
Right. Thanks, Ed.
ARTIE
Okay, fair enough. You're right.
I'm not a talking tree.
ARTIE
But you know...
...a good friend of mine once told me...
ARTIE
...that just because people treat you
like a villain, or an ogre...
ARTIE
...or just some loser...
...doesn't mean you are one.
ARTIE
The thing that matters most
is what you think of yourself.
ARTIE
If there's something you really want,
or someone you really want to be...
ARTIE
...then the only person standing
in your way is you.
RUMPLESTILTSKIN
- Me?
- Get him!
ARTIE
No, no, no!
What I mean is each of you...
ARTIE
...is standing in your own way.
HEADLESS HORSEMAN
I always wanted to play the flute.
EVIL QUEEN
I'd like to open up a spa... in France!
CAPTAIN HOOK
I grow daffodils. And they're beautiful.
PRINCE CHARMING
A new era finally begins!
Now all of you...
PRINCE CHARMING
...bow before your King!
SHREK
You need to work on your aim.
PRINCE CHARMING
This was supposed to be
my happily ever after!
SHREK
Now I guess you need to keep looking...
...because I'm not giving up mine.
PRINCE CHARMING
Mommy?
SHREK
It's yours if you want it you know.
But this time it's your choice.
DONKEY
Arthur!
ALL
Artie! Artie! Artie! Artie!
MERLIN
Excuse me. That's my seat.
PUSS
Okay, Senor Hocusy-Pocusy, the time
has come to rectify some wrongs!
DONKEY
Although I have been enjoying
these cat baths.
PUSS
Please say you didn't.
MERLIN
All right, all right! Look.
You're gonna feel a little pinch and possibly
lower intestinal discomfort...
MERLIN
...but this should do the trick.
PUSS & DONKEY
- Are you?
- I'm me again!
PUSS & DONKEY
- And I am not you!
- All right!
MERLIN
Oops.
Ah, never mind.
SHREK
What did I tell you?
I think the kid's going to be a great king.
FIONA
Well, for what it's worth,
you would have, too.
SHREK
I have something
much more important in mind.
SHREK
Finally.
OGRE BABIES
Dada.
MUSIC
~ Was I wrong about the world?
It's a beautiful new place ~
DONKEY
I smell Shrek Junior!
MUSIC
~ Where else could a creep like me ~
~ Meet such a pretty face ~
MUSIC
~ Meeting every day with the rising sun ~
~ Looking up, it's looking like ~
MUSIC
~ My losing streak is done ~
DONKEY
Peek-a-boo!
QUEEN
A bouncy, bouncy, boy!
MUSIC
~ Used to always feel like ~
~ Wished that I was dressed better ~
NANNY DWARF
Where's the baby?
MUSIC
~ Never had a lot of luck
Until I finally met her ~
MUSIC
~ Meeting every day with the rising sun ~
~ Looking up, it's looking like ~
MUSIC
~ My losing streak is done ~
Well... what shall we do now?
SHREK
I got it.
DONKEY
Puss and Donkey, baby!
Once again, come on!
MUSIC
~ I want to thank you for letting me
be myself ~
MUSIC
~ Again! ~
~ Look at my hips! ~
MUSIC
~ I want to thank you for letting me
be myself ~
MUSIC
~ Again! ~
~ - Break it down!
- Let's go! ~
MUSIC
~ Stiff all in the collar ~
~ Fluffy in the face ~
MUSIC
~ Chit chat chatter trying ~
~ Stuffy in the place ~
MUSIC
~ Thank you for the par-tay ~
~ But I could never stay ~
MUSIC
~ I'm sorry. ~
~ I got many things on my mind ~
MUSIC
~ But the word's in the way ~
~ And I want to thank you for letting me
be myself ~
MUSIC
~ Again ~
~ Different strokes for different folks ~
MUSIC
~ Thank you for letting me be myself ~
~ Again ~
MUSIC
~ Break it down! ~