PRINCE CHARMING
Once upon a time in a
kingdom far, far away,
PRINCE CHARMING
the king and queen were blessed
with a beautiful baby girl.
PRINCE CHARMING
And throughout the land,
everyone was happy...
PRINCE CHARMING
until the sun went down
and they saw that their daughter was
cursed with a frightful enchantment
PRINCE CHARMING
that took hold each
and every night.
PRINCE CHARMING
Desperate, they sought the
help of a fairy godmother
PRINCE CHARMING
who had them lock the young
princess away in a tower,
PRINCE CHARMING
there to await the kiss... of
the handsome Prince Charming.
SOUND FX
(HORSE WHINNIES)
PRINCE CHARMING
It was he who would chance
the perilous journey
PRINCE CHARMING
through blistering cold
and scorching desert
PRINCE CHARMING
travelling for many
days and nights,
PRINCE CHARMING
risking life and limb
to reach the Dragon's keep.
SOUND FX
(CROWS CAW)
PRINCE CHARMING
For he was the bravest,
and most handsome...
PRINCE CHARMING
in all the land.
And it was destiny that his kiss
PRINCE CHARMING
would break the dreaded curse.
He alone would climb to the
highest room of the tallest tower
PRINCE CHARMING
to enter the princess's chambers, cross
the room to her sleeping silhouette,
PRINCE CHARMING
pull back the gossamer curtains
to find her... (GASPS)
WOLFIE
What?
PRINCE CHARMING
- Princess... Fiona?
WOLFIE
- No!
PRINCE CHARMING
(SIGHS RELIEF) Oh, thank heavens.
Where is she?
WOLFIE
- She's on her honeymoon.
PRINCE CHARMING
- Honeymoon? With whom?
MUSIC
(COUNTING CROWS:
ACCIDENTALLY IN LOVE)
MUSIC
So she said what's
the problem, baby?
MUSIC
What's the problem?
I don't know.
MUSIC
Well, maybe I'm in love.
Think about it everytime
I think about it.
MUSIC
Can't stop thinking about it.
How much longer will
it take to cure this?
MUSIC
Just to cure it, 'cause
I can't ignore it.
MUSIC
If it's love, love.
Makes me wanna turn
around and face me.
MUSIC
But I don't know
nothing about love.
MUSIC
Oh, come on, come on
SOUND FX
- (SCREAMS)
MUSIC
- Turn a little faster.
Come on, come on.
MUSIC
The world will follow after.
Come on, come on.
MUSIC
Everybody's after love.
So I said I'm a
snowball running.
MUSIC
Running down into this spring
that's coming all this love.
MUSIC
Melting under blue skies
belting out sunlight.
MUSIC
Shimmering love.
Well, baby, I surrender.
MUSIC
To the strawberry ice cream.
Never ever end of
all this love.
MUSIC
Well, I didn't mean to do it.
But there's no
escaping your love.
MUSIC
These lines of lightning
mean we're never alone.
MUSIC
Never alone, no, no.
Come on, come on.
MUSIC
Jump a little higher.
Come on, come on.
MUSIC
If you feel a little lighter.
Come on, come on.
MUSIC
We were once upon
a time in love.
FIONA
Hyah!
MUSIC
We're accidentally in love.
Accidentally in love.
MUSIC
Accidentally.
I'm in love, I'm in love,
I'm in love, I'm in love.
MUSIC
Accidentally in love.
I'm in love.
MUSIC
SHREK
It's so good to be home!
SOUND FX
- (DISTANT SINGING)
- (GIGGLING)
DONKEY
Just you and me and...
SOUND FX
(DONKEY SINGS)
DONKEY
- Two can be as bad as one...
SHREK
- Donkey?
DONKEY
Shrek! Fiona! Aren't you
two a sight for sore eyes!
DONKEY
Give us a hug, Shrek,
you old love machine.
SOUND FX
(CHUCKLES)
DONKEY
And look at you, Mrs. Shrek. How
about a side of sugar for the steed?
FIONA
Donkey, what are you doing here?
DONKEY
Taking care of your
love nest for you.
SHREK
Oh, you mean like... sorting the
mail and watering the plants?
DONKEY
- Yeah, and feeding the fish!
SHREK
- I don't have any fish.
DONKEY
You do now. I call that one
Shrek and the other Fiona.
DONKEY
That Shrek is a rascally devil.
Get your...
SHREK
Look at the time. I guess
you'd better be going.
DONKEY
Don't you want to tell me about your trip?
Or how about a game of Parcheesi?
FIONA
Actually, Donkey? Shouldn't you
be getting home to Dragon?
DONKEY
Oh, yeah, that.
I don't know. She's been all
moody and stuff lately.
DONKEY
I thought I'd move in with you.
FIONA
You know we're always
happy to see you, Donkey.
SHREK
But Fiona and I are married now.
We need a little time, you
know, to be together.
SHREK
Just with each other.
Alone.
DONKEY
Say no more. You don't have
to worry about a thing.
DONKEY
I will always be here to make
sure nobody bothers you.
SHREK
- Donkey!
DONKEY
- Yes, roomie?
SHREK
You're bothering me.
DONKEY
Oh, Okay. All right, cool.
I guess...
DONKEY
Me and Pinocchio was going to
catch a tournament, anyway, so...
DONKEY
Maybe I'll see y'all Sunday
for a barbecue or something.
SHREK
He'll be fine. Now,
where were we?
SHREK
(GIGGLES) Oh.
I think I remember.
SHREK
- Donkey!
FIONA
- (FIONA YELPS)
DONKEY
I know, I know! Alone! I'm going!
I'm going.
DONKEY
What do you want me to
tell these other guys?
SOUND FX
(FANFARE)
MUSIC
(THEME TO HAWAII FIVE-O)
INQUISITOR
Enough, Reggie.
(CLEARS THROAT) "Dearest
Princess Fiona."
INQUISITOR
"You are hereby summoned to
the Kingdom of Far, Far Away"
INQUISITOR
"for a royal ball in
celebration of your marriage"
INQUISITOR
"at which time the King"
"will bestow his royal blessing...
upon you and your..."
INQUISITOR
uh..."Prince Charming.
"Love, the King and Queen
of Far, Far Away."
INQUISITOR
"Aka Mom and Dad."
FIONA
Mom and Dad?
SHREK
- Prince Charming?
DONKEY
- Royal ball? Can I come?
SHREK
- We're not going.
FIONA & DONKEY
- (BOTH) What?
SHREK
I mean, don't you think
they might be a bit...
SHREK
shocked to see you like this?
FIONA
(CHUCKLES) Well, they
might be a bit surprised.
FIONA
But they're my parents, Shrek.
They love me.
FIONA
And don't worry.
They'll love you, too.
SHREK
Yeah, right.
Somehow I don't think I'll be
welcome at the country club.
FIONA
Stop it. They're
not like that.
SHREK
How do you explain Sergeant Pompous
and the Fancy Pants Club Band?
FIONA
Oh, come on! You could at
least give them a chance.
SHREK
To do what? Sharpen
their pitchforks?
FIONA
No! They just want to
give you their blessing.
SHREK
Oh, great. Now I
need their blessing?
FIONA
If you want to be a part
of this family, yes!
SHREK
Who says I want to be
part of this family?
FIONA
You did! When you married me!
SHREK
Well, there's some
fine print for you!
FIONA
(EXASPERATED SIGH) So that's it.
You won't come?
SHREK
Trust me. It's a bad idea.
We are not going!
SHREK
And that's final!
DONKEY
Come on! We don't
want to hit traffic!
GINGY
Don't worry! We'll
take care of everything.
SOUND FX
(ALL CHEER)
PINOCCHIO
- Hey, wait for me. Oof!
SOUND FX
- (GLASS BREAKS)
PINOCCHIO
(SIGHS)
MUSIC
(CHIC: LE FREAK)
DONKEY
Hit it! Move 'em on! Head 'em up! Head
'em up, move 'em on! Head 'em up!
DONKEY
Rawhide! Move 'em on!
Head 'em up!
DONKEY
Move 'em on! Move 'em on!
Head 'em up! Rawhide!
DONKEY
Ride 'em up! Move 'em on! Head 'em up!
Move 'em on! Rawhide!
DONKEY
Knock 'em out! Pound 'em dead!
Make 'em tea!
DONKEY
Buy 'em drinks!
Meet their mamas!
Milk 'em hard!
DONKEY
Rawhide! Yee-haw!
- Are we there yet?
SHREK
- No.
DONKEY
- Are we there yet?
FIONA
- Not yet.
DONKEY
- Okay, are we there yet?
FIONA
- No.
DONKEY
- Are we there yet?
SHREK
- No!
DONKEY
- Are we there yet?
SHREK
- Yes.
DONKEY
- Really?
SHREK
- No!
DONKEY
- Are we there yet?
FIONA
- No!
DONKEY
- Are we there yet?
SHREK
- We are not!
DONKEY
- Are we there yet?
SHREK & FIONA
- No!
DONKEY
- Are we there yet?
SHREK
DONKEY
- That's not funny. That's really immature.
SHREK
DONKEY
- This is why nobody likes ogres.
SHREK
DONKEY
- Your loss!
SHREK
DONKEY
- I'm gonna just stop talking.
SHREK
- Finally!
DONKEY
This is taking forever, Shrek. There's
no in-flight movie or nothing!
SHREK
The Kingdom of Far,
Far Away, Donkey.
SHREK
That's where we're going.
Far, far...
SHREK
(SOFTLY) away!
DONKEY
All right, all right, I get it.
I'm just so darn bored.
SHREK
Well, find a way to
entertain yourself.
DONKEY
(SIGHS)
(DEEP SIGH)
DONKEY
(CLICKS TONGUE)
(POPPING)
DONKEY
- (POPPING)
SHREK
- (EXASPERATED SIGH)
For five minutes...
SHREK
Could you not be yourself...
(SHOUTS)... for five minutes!
DONKEY
- (POPPING)
SHREK
- (SHRIEKS)
Are we there yet?
FIONA
- (CHUCKLES) Yes!
DONKEY
- Oh, finally!
SOUND FX
(FANFARE)
MUSIC
(LIPPS, INC: FUNKYTOWN)
DONKEY
Wow!
It's going to be champagne wishes
and caviar dreams from now on.
DONKEY
Hey, good-looking! We'll be
back to pick you up later!
MUSIC
Gotta make a move to a
town that's right for me.
SHREK
We are definitely not
in the swamp anymore.
GUARD
(WHISTLE) Halt!
MUSIC
Well, I talk about it, talk about
it, talk about it, talk about it.
TOWNSPEOPLE
Hey, everyone, look.
MUSIC
Talk about, talk
about movin'...
DONKEY
Hey, ladies! Nice day for a parade, huh?
You working that hat.
DONKEY
Swimming pools!
Movie stars!
SOUND FX
(CHEERING)
(APPLAUSE)
SOUND FX
(FANFARE)
MESSENGER
Announcing the
long-awaited return
MESSENGER
of the beautiful Princess
Fiona and her new husband.
FIONA
Well, this is it.
KING
- This is it.
CHAUFFEUR
MESSENGER
This is it.
SOUND FX
(FANFARE)
(FANFARE AND CHEERING STOP)
SOUND FX
(GASPS)
(TWEETING)
SOUND FX
(BABY WAILS)
DONKEY
Uh... why don't you guys go ahead?
I'll park the car.
SHREK
(CHUCKLES) So...
you still think this
was a good idea?
FIONA
Of course! Look. Mom and
Dad look happy to see us.
KING
- (SOFTLY) Who on earth are they?
QUEEN
- (SOFTLY) I think that's our little girl.
KING
That's not little! That's
a really big problem.
KING
Wasn't she supposed to kiss Prince
Charming and break the spell?
QUEEN
Well, he's no Prince Charming,
but they do look...
SHREK
(SOFTLY) Happy now? We came.
We saw them.
SHREK
Now let's go before
they light the torches.
FIONA
- They're my parents.
SHREK
- Hello? They locked you in a tower.
FIONA
That was for my own...
KING
Good! Here's our chance. Let's go back
inside and pretend we're not home.
QUEEN
Harold, we have to be...
SHREK
Quick! While they're not looking
we can make a run for it.
FIONA
Shrek, stop it!
Everything's gonna be...
KING
A disaster! There is no way...
FIONA
- You can do this.
SHREK
- I really...
KING
- Really...
QUEEN
- Don't...
SHREK
- want...
FIONA
- to...
KING
- be...
SHREK
Here!
FIONA
Mom... Dad...
I'd like you to
meet my husband...
FIONA
Shrek.
SHREK
Well, um...
It's easy to see where Fiona
gets her good looks from.
SHREK
(CHUCKLES NERVOUSLY)
SOUND FX
(GULPS)
(BELCHES)
FIONA
- Excuse me.
SOUND FX
- (SHREK & Fiona LAUGH)
SHREK
Better out than in, I
always say, eh, Fiona?
SOUND FX
(BOTH GIGGLE)
SHREK
That's good.
I guess not.
DONKEY
What do you mean, "not on the list"?
Don't tell me you don't know who I am.
DONKEY
What's happening, everybody?
Thanks for waiting.
DONKEY
I had the hardest time
finding this place.
KING
No! No! Bad donkey! Bad! Down!
FIONA
No, Dad! It's all right. It's all right.
He's with us.
FIONA
- He helped rescue me from the dragon.
DONKEY
- That's me: The noble steed.
Waiter! How about a
bowl for the steed?
SHREK
Oh, boy.
SOUND FX
(SLURPS)
FIONA
- Um, Shrek?
SHREK
- Yeah?
Oh, sorry! Great soup, Mrs. Q.
SHREK
Mmm!
FIONA
No, no. Darling.
SHREK
(CHUCKLES NERVOUSLY) Oh!
QUEEN
So, Fiona, tell us
about where you live.
FIONA
Well...
Shrek owns his own land.
FIONA
- Don't you, honey?
SHREK
- Oh, yes!
It's in an enchanted forest
SHREK
abundant in squirrels and
cute little duckies and...
DONKEY
(LAUGHING) What?
I know you ain't talking
about the swamp.
KING
An ogre from a swamp.
Oh! How original.
QUEEN
I suppose that would be a fine
place to raise the children.
SOUND FX
- (SPLUTTERS)
- (CHOKES)
SHREK
It's a bit early to be
thinking about that, isn't it?
KING
- Indeed. I just started eating.
QUEEN
- Harold!
SHREK
- What's that supposed to mean?
FIONA
- Dad. It's great, Okay?
KING
- For his type, yes.
SHREK
- My type?
DONKEY
I got to go to the bathroom.
SERVANT
- Dinner is served!
DONKEY
- Never mind. I can hold it.
SERVANT
Bon appetit!
DONKEY
Oh, Mexican food!
My favourite.
QUEEN
Let's not sit here with
our tummies rumbling.
QUEEN
Everybody dig in.
SHREK
Don't mind if I do, Lillian.
KING
I suppose any grandchildren I
could expect from you would be...
SHREK
Ogres, yes!
QUEEN
Not that there's anything wrong with that.
Right, Harold?
KING
Oh, no! No! Of course, not!
That is, assuming you
don't eat your own young!
FIONA
Dad!
SHREK
No, we usually prefer the ones
who've been locked away in a tower!
FIONA
- Shrek, please!
KING
- I only did that because I love her.
SHREK
Aye, day care or
dragon-guarded castle.
KING
You wouldn't understand.
You're not her father!
DONKEY
It's so nice to have the
family together for dinner.
QUEEN
- Harold!
FIONA
- Shrek!
SHREK
- Fiona!
KING
FIONA
- Mom!
QUEEN
- Harold...
DONKEY
Donkey!
MUSIC
(GLISSANDO)
FAIRY GODMOTHER
Your fallen tears
have called to me.
FAIRY GODMOTHER
So, here comes
my sweet remedy.
FAIRY GODMOTHER
I know what every
princess needs.
FAIRY GODMOTHER
For her to live
life happily...
SOUND FX
(BOTH GASP)
FAIRY GODMOTHER
Oh, my dear. Oh, look at you.
You're all grown up.
FIONA
- Who are you?
FAIRY GODMOTHER
- Oh, sweet pea!
I'm your fairy godmother.
FIONA
- I have a fairy godmother?
FAIRY GODMOTHER
- Shush, shush.
Now, don't worry. I'm here
to make it all better.
FAIRY GODMOTHER
With just a...
Wave of my magic wand Your
troubles will soon be gone.
FAIRY GODMOTHER
With a flick of the wrist and just a flash
You'll land a prince with a ton of cash.
FAIRY GODMOTHER
A high-priced dress
made by mice no less.
FAIRY GODMOTHER
Some crystal glass pumps
And no more stress.
FAIRY GODMOTHER
Your worries will vanish,
your soul will cleanse.
FAIRY GODMOTHER
Confide in your very
own furniture friends.
FAIRY GODMOTHER
We'll help you set a
new fashion trend.
FAIRY GODMOTHER
- I'll make you fancy, I'll make you great.
- The kind of girl a prince would date!
FAIRY GODMOTHER
They'll write your name
on the bathroom wall...
FAIRY GODMOTHER
"For a happy ever after,
give Fiona a call!"
FAIRY GODMOTHER
A sporty carriage to ride in style,
Sexy man boy chauffeur, Kyle.
FAIRY GODMOTHER
Banish your blemishes, tooth decay,
Cellulite thighs will fade away.
FAIRY GODMOTHER
And oh, what the hey!
Have a bichon frisé!
FAIRY GODMOTHER
Nip and tuck, here and there to land
that prince with the perfect hair.
FAIRY GODMOTHER
Lipstick liners, shadows blush To
get that prince with the sexy tush.
FAIRY GODMOTHER
Lucky day, hunk buffet You and your
prince take a roll in the hay.
FAIRY GODMOTHER
You can spoon on the moon
With the prince to the tune.
FAIRY GODMOTHER
Don't be drab, you'll be fab Your
prince will have rock-hard abs.
FAIRY GODMOTHER
Cheese soufflé, Valentine's Day
Have some chicken fricassee!
FAIRY GODMOTHER
Nip and tuck, here and there To land
that prince with the perfect hair.
FIONA
Stop!
FAIRY GODMOTHER
(CHUCKLES) Look...
FIONA
Thank you very much,
Fairy Godmother,
FIONA
but I really don't
need all this.
SOUND FX
(GASPS AND MUTTERINGS
OF DISAPPROVAL)
FAIRY GODMOTHER
- Fine. Be that way.
FURNITURE
- We didn't like you, anyway.
SOUND FX
- (KNOCKING)
SHREK
- Fiona? Fiona?
SOUND FX
(DOG BARKS)
DONKEY
Oh! You got a puppy? All I
got in my room was shampoo.
FIONA
Oh, uh...
Fairy Godmother, furniture...
SOUND FX
(GIGGLES)
FIONA
I'd like you to meet
my husband, Shrek.
FAIRY GODMOTHER
Your husband? What? What did you say?
When did this happen?
FIONA
Shrek is the one who rescued me.
FAIRY GODMOTHER
- But that can't be right.
SHREK
- Oh, great, more relatives!
FIONA
She's just trying to help.
SHREK
Good! She can help us pack. Get
your coat, dear. We're leaving.
FIONA
- What?
DONKEY
- I don't want to leave.
SHREK
When did you decide this?
- Shortly after arriving.
FIONA
- Look, I'm sorry...
FAIRY GODMOTHER
No, that's all right.
I need to go, anyway.
FAIRY GODMOTHER
But remember, dear. If you
should ever need me...
FAIRY GODMOTHER
happiness...
is just a teardrop away.
SHREK
Thanks, but we've got all
the happiness we need.
SHREK
Happy, happy, happy...
FAIRY GODMOTHER
(LAUGHS) So I see.
Let's go, Kyle.
FIONA
- Very nice, Shrek.
SHREK
- What?
I told you coming
here was a bad idea.
FIONA
You could've at least tried
to get along with my father.
SHREK
I don't think I was going
to get Daddy's blessing,
SHREK
even if I did want it.
FIONA
Do you think it might be nice if
somebody asked me what I wanted?
SHREK
Sure. Do you want
me to pack for you?
FIONA
You're unbelievable!
You're behaving like a...
SHREK
- Go on! Say it!
FIONA
- Like an ogre!
SHREK
Here's a news flash for you!
Whether your parents like it or not...
I am an ogre!
SOUND FX
- (YELPS)
- (ROARS)
SHREK
And guess what, Princess?
That's not about to change.
FIONA
I've made changes for you, Shrek.
Think about that.
DONKEY
That's real smooth, Shrek.
"I'm an ogre!"
DONKEY
(MIMICS SHREK ROARING)
FIONA
(SNIFFLING)
KING
I knew this would happen.
QUEEN
You should.
You started it.
KING
I can hardly believe that, Lillian.
He's the ogre. Not me.
QUEEN
I think, Harold, you're taking
this a little too personally.
QUEEN
This is Fiona's choice.
KING
But she was supposed to choose
the prince we picked for her.
KING
I mean, you expect me to give
my blessings to this... thing?
QUEEN
Fiona does. And she'll never
forgive you if you don't.
QUEEN
I don't want to lose our
daughter again, Harold.
QUEEN
Oh, you act as if love
is totally predictable.
QUEEN
Don't you remember
when we were young?
QUEEN
We used to walk down by
the lily pond and...
KING
- they were in bloom...
QUEEN
- Our first kiss.
KING
It's not the same!
I don't think you realize that our
daughter has married a monster!
QUEEN
Oh, stop being
such a drama king.
KING
Fine! Pretend there's
nothing wrong!
KING
La, di, da, di, da!
Isn't it all wonderful!
KING
I'd like to know how it
could get any worse!
FAIRY GODMOTHER
- Hello, Harold.
SOUND FX
- (GASPS)
QUEEN
- What happened?
KING
- Nothing, dear!
Just the old hunting
wound playing up a bit!
SOUND FX
(CHUCKLES)
KING
I'll just stretch it
out here for a while.
FAIRY GODMOTHER
You better get in.
We need to talk.
KING
Actually, Fairy
Godmother, off to bed.
KING
(YAWNS) Already taken my pills, and
they tend to make me a bit drowsy.
KING
So, how about... we make
this a quick visit. What?
KING
Oh, hello. Ha-ha-ha!
So, what's new?
FAIRY GODMOTHER
You remember my son,
Prince Charming?
KING
Is that you? My gosh!
It's been years.
KING
When did you get back?
PRINCE CHARMING
Oh, about five minutes
ago, actually.
PRINCE CHARMING
After I endured blistering
winds, scorching desert...
PRINCE CHARMING
I climbed to the highest
room in the tallest tower...
FAIRY GODMOTHER
Mommy can handle this.
He endures blistering winds
and scorching desert!
FAIRY GODMOTHER
He climbs to the highest bloody
room of the tallest bloody tower...
FAIRY GODMOTHER
And what does he find?
Some gender-confused wolf
telling him that his princess
FAIRY GODMOTHER
is already married.
KING
It wasn't my fault. He
didn't get there in time.
FAIRY GODMOTHER
Stop the car!
SOUND FX
(CRASH)
FAIRY GODMOTHER
Harold.
You force me to do something
I really don't want to do.
KING
(GASPS) Where are we?
ATTENDANT
Hi. Welcome to Friar's Fat Boy!
May I take your order?
FAIRY GODMOTHER
My diet is ruined! I hope you're happy.
Er... okay.
FAIRY GODMOTHER
Two Renaissance Wraps, no Mayo...
chili rings...
PRINCE CHARMING
- I'll have the Medieval Meal.
FAIRY GODMOTHER
- One Medieval Meal and, Harold...
- Curly fries?
KING
- No, thank you.
FAIRY GODMOTHER
- Sourdough soft taco, then?
KING
- No, really, I'm fine.
ATTENDANT
Your order, Fairy Godmother. This
comes with the Medieval Meal.
FAIRY GODMOTHER
There you are, dear.
We made a deal, Harold, and I assume you
don't want me to go back on my part.
KING
(SIGHS DEEPLY) Indeed not.
FAIRY GODMOTHER
So, Fiona and Charming
will be together.
KING
- Yes.
FAIRY GODMOTHER
- Believe me, Harold. It's what's best.
Not only for your daughter...
FAIRY GODMOTHER
but for your Kingdom.
KING
What am I supposed
to do about it?
FAIRY GODMOTHER
Use your imagination.
SOUND FX
(WHOOSHING)
(WHINNIES)
CYCLOPS
Oh...
Come on in, Your Majesty.
SOUND FX
(PIANO PLAYS, PEOPLE TALK)
MUSIC
I like my town.
With a little drop of poison.
MUSIC
Nobody knows...
SOUND FX
(BELCHES)
KING
(CLEARS THROAT) Excuse me.
FROG
Do I know you?
KING
No, you must be mistaking
me for someone else.
KING
Uh... excuse me. I'm looking
for the Ugly Stepsister.
KING
Ah! There you are. Right.
You see, I need to have
someone taken care of.
UGLY STEPSISTER
- Who's the guy?
KING
- Well, he's not a guy, per se.
Um... He's an ogre.
SOUND FX
(CROWD GASP)
UGLY STEPSISTER
Hey, buddy, let me clue you in.
There's only one fellow who can handle
a job like that, and, frankly...
UGLY STEPSISTER
he don't like to be disturbed.
KING
Where could I find him?
SOUND FX
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
KING
Hello?
PUSS
Who dares enter my room?
KING
Sorry! I hope I'm not interrupting, but
I'm told you're the one to talk to
KING
about an ogre problem?
PUSS
You are told correct.
But for this, I charge
a great deal of money.
KING
Would... this be enough?
PUSS
You have engaged my valuable
services, Your Majesty.
PUSS
Just tell me where I
can find this ogre.
MUSIC
(EELS: I NEED SOME SLEEP)
SOUND FX
(SNORING)
(CHIMES)
MUSIC
Everyone says I'm
getting down too low.
MUSIC
Everyone says you've
just gotta let it go.
MUSIC
You just gotta let it go.
I need some sleep.
MUSIC
Time to put the
old horse down.
MUSIC
I'm in too deep.
And the wheels keep
spinning round.
MUSIC
Everyone says you've
just gotta let it go.
MUSIC
Everyone says you've
just gotta let it go.
FIONA
Dear Knight, I pray that you take this
favour as a token of my gratitude.
SOUND FX
(PLAYS TUNE)
FIONA
Dear Diary...
Sleeping Beauty is having
a slumber party tomorrow,
FIONA
but Dad says I can't go. He
never lets me out after sunset.
FIONA
Dad says I'm going
away for a while.
FIONA
Must be like some
finishing school.
FIONA
Mom says that when
I'm old enough,
FIONA
my Prince Charming will
rescue me from my tower
FIONA
and bring me back
to my family,
FIONA
and we'll all live
happily ever after.
FIONA
Mrs. Fiona Charming.
(ECHOING) Mrs. Fiona Charming.
SOUND FX
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
KING
Sorry. I hope I'm not
interrupting anything.
SHREK
No, no. I was just reading a, uh...
a scary book.
KING
I was hoping you'd let me apologize
for my despicable behaviour earlier.
SHREK
- Okay...
KING
- I don't know what came over me.
Do you suppose we could pretend it
never happened and start over...
SHREK
- Look, Your Majesty, I just...
KING
- Please. Call me Dad.
SHREK
Dad. We both acted like ogres.
Maybe we just need some time
to get to know each other.
KING
Excellent idea! I was actually hoping
you might join me for a morning hunt.
KING
A little father-son time?
I know it would mean
the world to Fiona.
SOUND FX
(SIGHS)
KING
Shall we say, 7:30
by the old oak?
SOUND FX
(BIRDS TWITTER)
SHREK
Face it, Donkey!
We're lost.
DONKEY
We can't be lost. We followed the
King's instructions exactly.
DONKEY
"Head to the darkest
part of the woods..."
DONKEY
"Past the sinister trees with
scary-looking branches."
DONKEY
- The bush shaped like Shirley Bassey!
SHREK
- We passed that three times already!
DONKEY
You were the one who said
not to stop for directions.
SHREK
Oh, great. My one chance to fix
things up with Fiona's dad
SHREK
and I end up lost in
the woods with you!
DONKEY
Don't get huffy! I'm
only trying to help.
SHREK
I know! I know.
DONKEY
- I'm sorry, all right?
- Hey, don't worry about it.
SHREK
I just really need to make
things work with this guy.
DONKEY
Yeah, sure. Now let's
go bond with Daddy.
SOUND FX
(PURRING)
SHREK
Well, well, well, Donkey.
I know it was kind of a tender
moment back there, but the purring?
DONKEY
What? I ain't purring.
SHREK
Sure. What's next? A hug?
DONKEY
Hey, Shrek. Donkeys don't purr. What
do you think I am, some kind of a...
PUSS
Ha-ha! Fear me, if you dare!
(HISSES)
SHREK
Look! A little cat.
DONKEY
- Look out, Shrek! He got a piece!
SHREK
- It's a cat, Donkey.
Come here, little
kitty, kitty.
SHREK
Come on, little kitty. Come here.
Oh! Come here, little kitty.
SOUND FX
- (SCREAMING)
SHREK
- Whoa!
DONKEY
- Hold on, Shrek! I'm coming!
SHREK
- Come on! Get it off! Get it off!
Oh, God. Oh...
SHREK
No!
DONKEY
- Look out, Shrek! Hold still!
SHREK
- Get it off!
DONKEY
Shrek! Hold still!
- Did I miss?
SHREK
- No. You got them.
PUSS
Now, ye ogre, pray
for mercy from...
PUSS
Puss... in Boots!
SHREK
I'll kill that cat!
PUSS
Ah-ha-ha!
(COUGHS)
PUSS
(WHEEZES)
(RETCHES)
PUSS
(COUGHS)
- (CHUCKLES) Hairball.
DONKEY
- Oh! That is nasty!
SHREK
What should we do with him?
DONKEY
Take the sword and neuter him.
Give him the Bob Barker treatment.
PUSS
Oh, no! Por favor! Please!
I implore you! It was
nothing personal, Señor.
PUSS
I was doing it only
for my family.
PUSS
My mother, she is sick. And my
father lives off the garbage!
PUSS
The King offered me much in gold
and I have a litter of brothers...
SHREK
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Fiona's father paid
you to do this?
PUSS
The rich King? Sí.
SOUND FX
(SCREAMS)
SHREK
Well, so much for
Dad's royal blessing.
DONKEY
Don't feel bad. Almost everybody
that meets you wants to kill you.
SHREK
Gee, thanks.
Maybe Fiona would've been better off if
I were some sort of Prince Charming.
PUSS
That's what the King said.
Oh, uh... sorry. I thought that
question was directed at me.
DONKEY
Shrek, Fiona knows you'd
do anything for her.
SHREK
Well, it's not like I
wouldn't change if I could.
SHREK
I just... I just wish I
could make her happy.
SHREK
Hold the phone...
"Happiness."
SHREK
"A tear drop away."
Donkey! Think of the saddest thing
that's ever happened to you!
DONKEY
Aw, man, where do I begin?
First there was the time that old farmer
tried to sell me for some magic beans.
DONKEY
Then this fool had a party and he have
the guests trying to pin the tail on me.
DONKEY
Then they got drunk and start beating
me with a stick, going "Piñata!"
DONKEY
What is a piñata, anyway?
SHREK
No, Donkey! I need you to cry!
DONKEY
Don't go projecting on me.
I know you're feeling
bad, but you got to...
DONKEY
Aaaahh!
You little, hairy,
litter-licking sack of...
FAIRY GODMOTHER
What? Is it on? Is it on?
(CLEARS THROAT)
FAIRY GODMOTHER
This is Fairy Godmother.
I'm either away from my
desk or with a client.
FAIRY GODMOTHER
But if you come by the office, we'll
be glad to make you an appointment.
FAIRY GODMOTHER
Have a "happy ever after."
SHREK
Oh...
Are you up for a
little quest, Donkey?
DONKEY
That's more like it! Shrek and Donkey,
on another whirlwind adventure!
DONKEY
Ain't no stoppin' us now! Wooh!
We're on the move!
PUSS
- Stop, Ogre! I have misjudged you.
DONKEY
- Join the club. We've got jackets.
PUSS
On my honour, I am obliged to accompany
you until I have saved your life
PUSS
as you have spared me mine.
DONKEY
The position of annoying talking
animal has already been taken.
DONKEY
Let's go, Shrek. Shrek?
- Shrek!
SHREK
- Aw, come on, Donkey. Look at him...
in his wee little boots.
SHREK
You know, how many cats can wear boots?
Honestly.
SHREK
- Let's keep him!
DONKEY
- Say what?
SOUND FX
(PURRS)
SHREK
Ahh!
Listen. He's purring!
DONKEY
- Oh, so now it's cute.
SHREK
- Come on, Donkey. Lighten up.
DONKEY
Lighten up? I should lighten up? Look
who's telling who to lighten up!
FIONA
(GIGGLES) Shrek!
SOUND FX
(BARKS)
FIONA
Shrek?
QUEEN
They're both festive,
aren't they?
QUEEN
What do you think, Harold?
KING
Um... Yes, yes. Fine. Fine.
SOUND FX
(SIGHS)
QUEEN
Try to at least pretend you're interested
in your daughter's wedding ball.
KING
Honestly, Lillian, I
don't think it matters.
KING
How do we know there
will even be a ball?
FIONA
Mom. Dad.
QUEEN
- Oh, hello, dear.
KING
- What's that, Cedric? Right! Coming.
FIONA
Mom, have you seen Shrek?
QUEEN
I haven't. You should
ask your father.
QUEEN
Be sure and use small words, dear.
He's a little slow this morning.
CEDRIC
- Can I help you, Your Majesty?
KING
- Ah, yes! Um...
Mmm! Exquisite. What
do you call this dish?
CEDRIC
That would be the dog's
breakfast, Your Majesty.
KING
Ah, yes. Very good, then.
Carry on, Cedric.
FIONA
- Dad? Dad, have you seen Shrek?
KING
- No, I haven't, dear.
I'm sure he just went off
to look for a nice...
KING
mud hole to cool down in.
You know, after your
little spat last night.
FIONA
Oh. You heard that, huh?
KING
The whole kingdom heard you.
I mean, after all, it is
in his nature to be...
KING
well, a bit of a brute.
FIONA
Him? You know, you didn't exactly
roll out the Welcome Wagon.
KING
Well, what did you expect?
Look at what he's done to you.
FIONA
Shrek loves me for who I am.
I would think you'd
be happy for me.
KING
Darling, I'm just thinking
about what's best for you.
KING
Maybe you should do the same.
SOUND FX
(BOTH WHISPER)
SHREK
No, really?
SOUND FX
(BOTH LAUGH)
SHREK
(Shrek) Shh...
Oh...
SOUND FX
(HOOTER BLASTS)
DONKEY
Oh, no. That's the old Keebler's place.
Let's back away slowly.
PUSS
That's the Fairy
Godmother's cottage.
PUSS
She's the largest producer of hexes
and potions in the whole kingdom.
SHREK
Then why don't we pop in there for a spell?
Ha-ha! Spell!
PUSS
(PUSS IN BOOTS SHRIEKS
WITH LAUGHTER)
PUSS
(PUSS IN BOOTS) He
makes me laugh.
SHREK
Hi. I'm here to see the...
RECEPTIONIST
The Fairy Godmother. I'm sorry.
She is not in.
FAIRY GODMOTHER
Jerome! Coffee and a Monte Cristo.
Now!
SOUND FX
(SIGHS)
Yes, Fairy Godmother.
Right away.
Look, she's not seeing
any clients today, Okay?
That's Okay, buddy.
We're from the union.
The union?
We represent the workers in all magical
industries, both evil and benign.
Oh! Oh, right.
Are you feeling at all
degraded or oppressed?
Uh... a little. We don't
even have dental.
They don't even have dental.
Okay, we'll just
have a look around.
Oh. By the way.
I think it'd be better if the Fairy
Godmother didn't know we were here.
- Know what I'm saying? Huh?
- Huh? Huh? Huh?
- Stop it.
- Of course. Go right in.
(VOICES AND GRINDING MACHINES)
(EXPLOSION)
A drop of desire.
(GIGGLES) Naughty!
A pinch of passion.
(LAUGHS)
And just a hint of...
lust!
(LAUGHS)
- (Shrek) Excuse me.
- (GASPS)
Sorry to barge in like this...
What in Grimm's name
are you doing here?
Well, it seems that Fiona's
not exactly happy.
Oh-ho-ho!
And there's some question
as to why that is?
Well, let's explore
that, shall we?
Ah. P, P, P. Princess.
Cinderella.
Here we are. "Lived happily
ever after." Oh...
(LAUGHS) No ogres!
Let's see. Snow White.
A handsome prince.
Oh, no ogres.
Sleeping Beauty. Oh, no ogres!
Hansel and Gretel? No!
Thumbelina? No.
The Golden Bird, the Little
Mermaid, Pretty Woman...
No, no, no, no, no!
You see, ogres don't
live happily ever after.
All right, look, lady!
Don't you point... those
dirty green sausages at me!
Your Monte Cristo and coffee.
Oh! Sorry.
Ah... that's okay.
We were just leaving.
Very sorry to have wasted
your time, Miss Godmother.
Just... go.
Come on, guys.
(WHISTLES TUNE)
TGIF, eh, buddy?
Working hard or hardly
working, eh, Mac?
Get your fine Corinthian footwear
and your cat cheeks out of my face!
Man, that stinks!
You don't exactly smell
like a basket of roses.
- Well, one of these has got to help.
- I was just concocting this very plan!
Already our minds
are becoming one.
Whoa, whoa. If we need an expert on
licking ourselves, we'll give you a call.
Shrek, this is a bad idea.
Look. Make yourself
useful and go keep watch.
Puss, do you think you
could get to those on top?
No problema, boss. In
one of my nine lives,
I was the great cat burglar
of Santiago de Compostela.
Ha-ha-ha-ha!
Shrek, are you off your nut?
Donkey, keep watch.
Keep watch? Yeah,
I'll keep watch.
I'll watch that wicked witch come and
whammy a world of hurt up your backside.
I'll laugh, too. I'll
be giggling to myself.
- What do you see?
- Toad Stool Softener?
I'm sure a nice BM is the perfect
solution for marital problems.
- Elfa Seltzer?
- Uh-uh.
- Hex Lax?
- No! Try "handsome."
Sorry. No handsome.
Hey! How about
"Happily Ever After"?
Well, what does it do?
It says "Beauty Divine."
In some cultures, donkeys are
revered as the wisest of creatures.
Especially us talking ones.
(GASPS) Donkey!
That'll have to do.
We've got company.
Can we get on with this?
Hurry!
Nice catch, Donkey!
Finally! A good use
for your mouth.
(PETE YORN: EVER
FALLEN IN LOVE)
Come on!
You spurn my natural emotions.
You make me feel like
dirt and I'm hurt.
And if I start a commotion.
I run the risk of losing
you and that's worse.
Ever fallen in love with
someone, ever fallen in love.
In love with someone,
ever fallen in love.
In love with someone you shouldn't
have fallen in love with.
Ever fallen in love with
someone, ever fallen in love.
In love with someone,
ever fallen in love.
With someone you shouldn't
have fallen in love with.
Fallen in love with.
Ever fallen in love with someone you
shouldn't have fallen in love with
I don't care whose fault it is.
Just get this place cleaned up!
And somebody bring me something deep
fried and smothered in chocolate!
- Mother!
- Charming. Sweetheart.
This isn't a good time, pumpkin.
Mama's working.
Whoa, what happened here?
- The ogre, that's what!
- What? Where is he, Mom?
I shall rend his head
from his shoulders!
I will smite him
where he stands!
He will rue the very day he
stole my kingdom from me!
Oh, put it away, Junior!
You're still going to be king.
We'll just have to come up
with something smarter.
Pardon. Um...
Everything is accounted for, Fairy
Godmother, except for one potion.
What?
Oh...
I do believe we can make
this work to our advantage.
"Happily Ever After Potion.
Maximum strength."
"For you and your true love."
"If one of you drinks this,
you both will be fine."
"Happiness, comfort
and beauty divine."
- You both will be fine?
- I guess it means it'll affect Fiona, too.
Hey, man, this don't feel right. My
donkey senses are tingling all over.
Drop that jug o' voodoo and
let's get out of here.
It says, "Beauty Divine."
How bad can it be?
(SNEEZES)
See, you're allergic to that stuff.
You'll have a reaction.
And if you think that I'll be smearing
Vapo Rub over your chest, think again!
Boss, just in case there is
something wrong with the potion...
allow me to take the first sip.
It would be an honour to lay
my life on the line for you.
Oh, no, no. I don't think so.
If there'll be any animal
testing, I'll do it.
That's the best friend's job.
Now give me that bottle.
How do you feel?
I don't feel any different.
I look any different?
You still look
like an ass to me.
Maybe it doesn't
work on donkeys.
- Well, here's to us, Fiona.
- Shrek?
- You drink that, there's no going back.
- I know.
- No more wallowing in the mud?
- No more itchy butt crack?
- I know!
- But you love being an ogre!
But I love Fiona more.
Shrek, no! Wait!
(GURGLING)
(FARTS)
Got to be... I think you grabbed
the "Farty Ever After" potion.
Maybe it's a dud.
Or maybe Fiona and I
were never meant to be.
(THUNDER RUMBLES)
Uh-oh. What did I tell you?
I feel something coming on.
I don't want to die. I don't want to die.
I don't want to die!
Oh, sweet sister, mother of mercy.
I'm melting!
It's just the rain, Donkey.
(CHUCKLES) Oh.
Don't worry. Things seem bad
because it's dark and rainy
and Fiona's father hired a
sleazy hitman to whack you.
(HISSES)
It'll be better in the morning.
You'll see...
The sun'll come out...
Tomorrow
(YAWNS)
Bet your bottom...
Bet my bottom?
I'm coming, Elizabeth!
Donkey?
Are you all right?
- Hey, boss. Let's shave him.
- D-Donkey?
(GROANS)
(PUSS IN BOOTS SHRIEKS)
There you are! We
missed you at dinner.
What is it, darling?
Dad...
I've been thinking
about what you said.
And I'm going to
set things right.
Ah! Excellent! That's my girl.
It was a mistake to
bring Shrek here.
I'm going to go
out and find him.
And then we'll go back to
the swamp where we belong.
(LILLIAN) Fiona, please!
Let's not be rash, darling. You
can't go anywhere right now.
(RAIN PATTERS)
(BOTH) Fiona!
Look, I told you he was here. Look at him!
Quiet. Look at him.
(SHREK GROANS)
Good morning, sleepyhead.
(SHREK SHOUTS)
(ALL) Good morning!
We love your kitty!
- (Shrek) Oh... My head...
- Here, I fetched a pail of water.
Thanks.
Uhh!
Aahh!
Oh...
A cute button nose?
Thick, wavy locks?
Taut, round buttocks?
I'm... I'm...
- Gorgeous!
- I'll say.
I'm Jill. What's your name?
- Um... Shrek.
- Shrek? Wow. Are you from Europe?
- You're tense.
- I want to rub his shoulders.
- I got it covered.
- I don't have anything to rub.
Get in line.
- Have you seen my donkey?
- Who are you calling donkey?
- Donkey? You're a...
- A stallion, baby!
I can whinny.
(WHINNIES) I can count.
Look at me, Shrek!
I'm trotting!
That's some quality potion.
What's in that stuff?
"Oh, don't take the potion,
Mr. Boss, it's very bad."
Pah!
"Warning: Side effects may include
burning, itching, oozing, weeping."
"Not intended for heart
patients or those with...
nervous disorders."
I'm trotting, I'm trotting in place!
Yeah!
What?
Señor? "To make the effects
of this potion permanent",
"the drinker must obtain his
true love's kiss by midnight."
Midnight? Why is it
always midnight?
- Pick me! I'll be your true love!
- I'll be your true love.
I'll be true... enough.
Look, ladies, I already
have a true love.
(ALL) Oh...
And take it from me, Boss.
You are going to have
one satisfied princess.
And let's face it. You are
a lot easier on the eyes.
Inside you're the same
old mean, salty...
- Easy.
- Cantankerous, foul,
angry ogre you always been.
And you're still the
same annoying donkey.
- Yeah.
- (SIGHS)
Well...
Look out, Princess.
Here comes the new me.
First things first.
- We need to get you out of those clothes.
- (ALL GASP)
- Ready?
- Ready!
- (DONKEY SCREAMS)
- Driver, stop!
Oh, God! Help me, please!
My racing days are over!
I'm blind! Tell the truth.
Will I ever play
the violin again?
You poor creature!
Is there anything
I can do for you?
Well, I guess there
is one thing.
Take off the powdered wig and
step away from your drawers.
- Not bad.
- Not bad at all.
(BOTH LAUGH)
Father? Is everything
all right, Father?
Thank you, gentlemen!
Someday, I will repay you.
Unless, of course, I can't
find you or if I forget.
- (WHINNIES)
- (PUSS IN BOOTS, IN ANGRY SPANISH)
(BUTTERFLY BOUCHER: CHANGES)
Oh, yeah.
Ch-Ch-Ch-Ch-Changes Turn
and face the strange.
Ch-Ch-Changes.
Don't wanna be a richer one.
Ch-Ch-Ch-Ch-Changes.
Turn and face the strange.
Ch-Ch-Changes.
Just gonna have to
be a different man.
Time may change me.
But I can't trace time.
Halt!
Tell Princess Fiona her husband,
Sir Shrek, is here to see her.
Still don't know what
I was looking for.
And my time was running wild,
a million dead-end streets.
Every time I thought
I'd got it made.
It seemed the taste
was not so sweet
- (SCREAMS)
- Ch-Ch-Ch-Ch-Changes.
Turn and face the strange.
- Shrek?
- Ch-Ch-Changes.
Don't wanna be a richer one.
Time may change me.
But I can't trace time
Fiona?
Hello, handsome.
Shrek!
- Princess!
- Donkey?
Wow! That potion
worked on you, too?
What potion?
Shrek and I took some magic potion.
And well...
Now, we're sexy!
Shrek?
(PURRS)
For you, baby... I could be.
- Yeah, you wish.
- Donkey, where is Shrek?
He went inside looking for you.
Shrek?
Fiona! Fiona!
You want to dance, pretty boy?
Are you going so soon? Don't
you want to see your wife?
Fiona?
Shrek?
Aye, Fiona. It is me.
What happened to your voice?
The potion changed a
lot of things, Fiona.
But not the way I
feel about you.
Fiona?
- Charming?
- Do you think so?
(LAUGHS) Dad. I was so
hoping you'd approve.
- Um... Who are you?
- Mom, it's me, Shrek.
I know you never get a second
chance at a first impression,
but, well, what do you think?
(Shrek IN DISTANCE) Fiona!
Fiona!
- Fiona!
- Fiona, Fiona! Ho-ho-ho!
Oh, shoot! I don't think
they can hear us, pigeon.
(SIGHS DEEPLY)
Don't you think you've already
messed her life up enough?
I just wanted her to be happy.
And now she can be.
Oh, sweetheart.
She's finally found the
prince of her dreams.
But look at me. Look
what I've done for her.
It's time you stop living
in a fairy tale, Shrek.
She's a princess,
and you're an ogre.
That's something no amount
of potion will ever change.
But...
I love her.
If you really love her...
you'll let her go.
(NICK CAVE: PEOPLE
AIN'T NO GOOD)
Shrek?
Señor.
What's going on?
Where are you going?
You wouldn't have had anything to
do with this, would you, Harold?
People just ain't no good.
I think that's
well understood.
There you go, boys.
Just leave the bottle, Doris.
Hey. Why the long face?
It was all just a
stupid mistake.
I never should have rescued her
from that tower in the first place.
I hate Mondays.
I can't believe you'd walk away from
the best thing that happened to you.
What choice do I have?
She loves that pretty
boy, Prince Charming.
Come on. Is he really
that good-looking?
Are you kidding?
He's gorgeous!
He has a face that looks like
it was carved by angels.
- Oh. He sounds dreamy.
- You know...
shockingly, this isn't
making me feel any better.
Look, guys. It's for the best.
Mom and Dad approve,
and Fiona gets the man
she's always dreamed of.
Everybody wins.
Except for you.
I don't get it, Shrek.
You love Fiona.
Aye.
And that's why I
have to let her go.
Excuse me, is she here?
She's, uh... in the back.
Oh, hello again.
Fairy Godmother. Charming.
You'd better have a good reason for
dragging us down here, Harold.
Well, I'm afraid Fiona isn't really...
warming up to Prince Charming.
- FYI, not my fault.
- No, of course it's not, dear.
I mean, how charming can I be
when I have to pretend
I'm that dreadful ogre?
No, no, it's nobody's fault.
Perhaps it's best if we just
call the whole thing off, okay?
- (BOTH) What?
- You can't force someone to fall in love!
I beg to differ. I
do it all the time!
Have Fiona drink this and she'll fall
in love with the first man she kisses,
which will be Charming.
- Umm... no.
- What did you say?
I can't. I won't do it.
Oh, yes, you will.
If you remember, I helped you
with your happily ever after.
And I can take it
away just as easily.
Is that what you want? Is it?
- No.
- Good boy.
Now, we have to go.
I need to do Charming's
hair before the ball.
He's hopeless. He's all
high in the front.
He can never get to the back. You
need someone to do the back.
Oh. Thank you, Mother.
(DONKEY) Mother?
Um... Mary! A talking horse!
The ogre!
Stop them! Thieves! Bandits!
Stop them!
(ANNOUNCER) The abs are fab and
it's gluteus to the maximus
here at tonight's Far, Far
Away Royal Ball blowout!
The coaches are lined up as the
cream of the crop pours out of them
like Miss Muffet's
curds and whey.
Everyone who's anyone
has turned out
to honour Princess Fiona
and Prince Shrek.
And, oh my, the outfits
look gorgeous!
Look! Hansel and Gretel!
What the heck are
the crumbs for?
And right behind them, Tom
Thumb and Thumbelina!
- Oh, aren't they adorable!
- (SCREAMING)
(WOMAN) Here comes
Sleeping Beauty!
Tired old thing.
Who's this? Who's this?
Who is this?
Oh. It's the one,
it's the only...
It's the Fairy Godmother!
Hello, Far, Far Away!
Can I get a whoop whoop?
May all your endings
be happy and...
Well, you know the rest!
We'll be right back with the
Royal Far, Far Away Ball
after these messages.
I hate these ball shows.
They bore me to tears. Flip
over to Wheel Of Torture!
I'm not flipping anywhere, sir,
until I see Shrek and Fiona.
Whizzes on you guys.
Hey, mice, pass me
a buffalo wing!
No, to your left. Your left!
- Tonight on "Knights"...
- Now here's a good show!
We got a white bronco heading east
into the forest. Requesting backup.
It's time to teach
these madcap mammals
their "devil may mare"
attitudes just won't fly.
Why you grabbing me?
Police brutality!
I have to talk to
Princess Fiona!
- We warned you!
- Ow! Ow!
Did someone let the
cat out of the bag?
You capitalist pig dogs!
(SHRIEKS)
- Catnip!
- That's not mine.
Find Princess Fiona!
I'm a donkey!
Tell her Shrek... I'm
her husband, Shrek!
Quick! Rewind it!
I'm her husband, Shrek! Ow!
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
Darling?
Ah. I thought I might
find you here.
How about a nice hot cup
of tea before the ball?
I'm not going.
The whole Kingdom's turned out
to celebrate your marriage.
There's just one problem.
That's not my husband.
I mean, look at him.
Yes, he is a bit different,
but people change for
the ones they love.
You'd be surprised how much
I changed for your mother.
Change?
He's completely lost his mind!
Why not come down to the ball
and give him another chance?
You might find you
like this new Shrek.
But it's the old one I
fell in love with, Dad.
I'd give anything
to have him back.
Darling. That's mine. Decaf.
Otherwise I'm up all night.
Thanks.
I got to get out of here!
You can't lock us up like this!
Let me go!
What about my Miranda rights?
You're supposed to say I have
the right to remain silent.
Nobody said I have the
right to remain silent!
You have the right
to remain silent.
What you lack is the capacity.
I must hold on before
I, too, go totally mad.
Shrek? Donkey?
Too late.
Gingy! Pinocchio!
Get us out of here!
Oh...
(THEME FROM MISSION
IMPOSSIBLE)
Fire in ze hole!
(EXPLOSION, RUMBLING)
Look out below!
Quick! Tell a lie!
- What should I say?
- Anything, but quick!
Say something crazy like "I'm
wearing ladies' underwear!"
I am wearing ladies' underwear.
- Are you?
- I most certainly am not!
It looks like you most
certainly am are!
- I am not!
- What kind?
- It's a thong!
- Oww! They're briefs!
- Are not.
- Are too!
- Are not!
Here we go. Hang tight.
(DONKEY) Wait, wait, wait!
Ow! Ow! Hey, hey, hey!
Ow!
- Excuse me?
- What? Puss!
Pardon me, would you
mind letting me go?
- Sorry, boss.
- Quit messing around!
We've got to stop that kiss!
I thought you was
going to let her go.
I was, but I can't let
them do this to Fiona.
Boom! That's what I like to hear.
Look who's coming around!
It's impossible!
We'll never get in.
The castle's guarded. There's
a moat and everything!
Folks, it looks like we're up chocolate
creek without a Popsicle stick.
- What?
- Do you still know the Muffin Man?
Well, sure! He's down
on Drury Lane. Why?
Because we're gonna need flour.
Lots and lots of flour.
Gingy!
Fire up the ovens, Muffin Man!
We've got a big order to fill!
(EVIL CHUCKLE)
(GINGY) It's alive!
(RATTLING)
(GASPING)
(WHINNIES) Run, run,
run, as fast you can!
(SCREAMING)
Go, baby, go!
There it is, Mongo!
To the castle!
(Shrek) No, you great stupid pastry!
Come on!
(ALL SHOUT)
(DONKEY) Mongo! Down here!
Look at the pony!
That's right! Follow
the pretty pony!
Pretty pony wants to
play at the castle!
(MONGO) Pretty pony.
Ladies and gentlemen.
Presenting Princess Fiona and
her new husband, Prince Shrek.
(APPLAUSE, CHEERING)
Shrek, what are you doing?
I'm just playing
the part, Fiona.
Is that glitter on your lips?
Mm. Cherry flavoured.
Want to taste?
- Ugh! What is with you?
- But, Muffin Cake...
(PIANO PLAYS)
C Minor, put it in C Minor.
Ladies and gentlemen.
(APPLAUSE, CHEERING)
I'd like to dedicate
this song to...
Princess Fiona and Prince Shrek.
Fiona, my Princess.
Will you honour me with a dance?
Where have all the
good men gone.
And where are all the gods?
(ALL CHANT) Dance!
Where's the
streetwise Hercules.
To fight the rising odds?
Since when do you dance?
Fiona, my dearest, if
there's one thing I know,
it's that love is
full of surprises.
Late at night I
toss and I turn.
And I dream of what I need.
Hit it!
I need a hero.
All right, big fella!
Let's crash this party!
Man the catapults!
Aim! Fire!
- Brace yourselves!
- Ooh! Purty!
(GROANING)
Not the gumdrop button!
(ENRAGED HOWLING)
Incoming!
Ha-ha! All right!
Somewhere after midnight
In my wildest fantasy.
Go, Mongo! Go!
Man the cauldrons!
After you, Mongo.
- That's it! Heave-ho!
- Watch out!
Shrek!
More heat, less foam!
Up where the mountains
Meet the heavens above.
Out where the lightning
Splits the sea.
I could swear there is someone
Somewhere watching me.
Heave! Ho!
(GINGY, SLOW-MOTION) No!
(MONGO GROANS)
(WHISTLES) Come on!
(CHEERING)
Look out!
- Be good.
- (WEEPING BITTERLY)
(SOBBING) He needs me!
Let me go!
Donkey!
Puss!
Go! Go! Your lady needs you! Go!
Today, I repay my debt.
(ALL) Aww...
(GROWLING) En garde!
He's gotta be strong And
he's gotta be fast.
And he's gotta be
fresh From the fight.
- I need a hero.
- Stop!
(DONKEY WHINNIES)
- Hey, you! Back away from my wife.
- Shrek?
You couldn't just go back to your
swamp and leave well enough alone.
- Now!
- Pigs und blanket!
Pinocchio! Get the wand!
I see London! I see France!
Whah!
I'm a real boy!
Ah! Ah! Aaahh!
Catch!
Donkey!
Oh!
I'm a real boy. Aah!
- Ha!
- Ah.
That's mine!
Pray for mercy, from Puss...
And Donkey!
She's taken the potion!
Kiss her now!
No!
- Hi-ya!
- (CROWD GASP)
- Fiona.
- Shrek.
Harold! You were supposed
to give her the potion!
Well, I guess I gave
her the wrong tea.
- (CHARMING) Mommy!
- Mommy?
(GROWLS) I told you.
Ogres don't live
happily ever after.
(SCREAMS)
Woo!
Ha!
(BREATHES DEEPLY)
(GASPING) Oh, Dad!
(SOBBING)
- Is he?
- Yup.
(CROAKING)
He croaked.
Harold?
Dad?
I'd hoped you'd never
see me like this.
- And he gave you a hard time!
- Donkey!
No, no, he's right. I'm sorry.
To both of you.
I only wanted what
was best for Fiona.
But I can see now...
she already has it.
Shrek, Fiona...
Will you accept an old
frog's apologies...
and my blessing?
Harold? I'm sorry, Lillian.
I just wish I could be
the man you deserve.
You're more that man today
than you ever were...
warts and all.
(RIBBITS)
(CLOCK CHIMES)
Boss! The Happily
Ever After Potion!
Midnight!
Fiona. Is this what you want?
To be this way forever?
- What?
- Because if you kiss me now...
we can stay like this.
You'd do that?
- For me?
- Yes.
I want what any princess wants.
To live happily ever after...
with the ogre I married.
Whatever happens,
I must not cry!
You cannot make me cry!
(SOBBING)
(CLOCK CHIMES)
Whoa!
No. No, no. Aaah! Ow.
Oh, no.
(SIGHS)
(LAUGHS) Hey. You still look
like a noble steed to me.
(GIGGLES) Now, where were we?
Oh. I remember.
(GIGGLING)
(APPLAUSE)
Hey! Isn't we supposed
to be having a fiesta?
Uno, dos, cuatro, hit it!
(EDDIE MURPHY/ANTONIO BANDERAS:
LMN' LA VIDA LOCA)
Puss and Donkey, y'all...
She's into superstitions.
Black cats and voodoo dolls.
- Sing it, Puss!
- I feel a premonition.
That girl's gonna
make me fall.
Here we go!
She's into new sensations.
New kicks in the candlelight.
She's got a new addiction.
For every day and night.
She'll make you take
your clothes off.
And go dancing in the rain.
She'll make you live
her crazy life.
But she'll take
away your pain.
Like a bullet to your brain.
Upside inside out.
Living la vida loca.
Hey gorgeous!
Her lips are devil red.
And her skin's the
colour of mocha.
She will wear you out.
- Living la vida loca.
- (DONKEY) She livin' it loca!
Living la vida loca
- (DONKEY) Say it one more time now!
- Living the vida loca
(PUSS IN BOOTS JAMMING)
(PUSS IN BOOTS) Hey,
Donkey, that's Spanish!
She'll push and pull you down.
Living la vida loca.
She will wear you out.
She'll push and pull you down.
Living the vida loca.
Her lips are devil red.
And her skin's the
colour of mocha.
She will wear you out.
Living la vida loca.
All by myself.
Don't wanna be.
All by myself anymore...
Amigo, we are off to
the Kit-Kat Club.
Come on, join us.
Thanks, compadre. I'm...
I'm not in the mood.
We will cheer you up!
Find you a nice burro!
(SHRIEKING)
Hey, baby!
Hey, that's my girl!
Yeah! All right!
Baby, where you been?
- (CRIES)
- I'm sorry, too.
I should've stayed. But Shrek
had this thing he had to do.
What? Say it one more time.
What you talking about?
Are you serious?
- (COOING)
- (GASPING)
- Papa!
- (SCREAMING)
- (COOING, SQUEALING)
- (CHUCKLING)
Look at our little
mutant babies!